<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
    <title>Books on The world as a stage</title>
    <link>https://theworldasastage.com/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on The world as a stage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://theworldasastage.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
        <title>5 great books about creativity</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/5-great-books-about-creativity/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/5-great-books-about-creativity/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here are five great books about creativity. These are very good books where you can experience different aspect of creativity: How it became a culture in a creative company like Pixar (Creativity Inc), how one person can fight to maintain it in a huge industry (Orbiting the Giant Hairball), the importance of mistakes in the creative process (The Art of Making Mistakes), how an author can make crazy idea with everyday things (H2G2) and finally in the best example of Art&amp;amp;Science I know, magic (Magical Mathematics).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/horizontal-slim-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; width:100%;}
   
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://theworldasastage.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b&amp;amp;id=32885e90b3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
    Subscribe to my newsletter to receive one new book recommendation every week.
  &lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34; placeholder=&#34;email address&#34; required&gt;
    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b_32885e90b3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;books&#34; name=&#34;SIGNUPWHY&#34; class=&#34;required&#34; id=&#34;mce-SIGNUPWHY&#34;&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h2 id=&#34;creativity-inc-overcoming-the-unseen-forces-that-stand-in-the-way-of-true-inspiration-https-www-goodreads-com-book-show-18077903-creativity-inc-from-search-true&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18077903-creativity-inc?from_search=true&#34;&gt;Creativity Inc: Overcoming the unseen forces that stand in the way of true inspiration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-creativity.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:200px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ed Catmull, a co-founder of Pixar Studios, tell in this book how he worked with his team to build and maintain a creative culture in this incredible company. He also explains how, when bought by Pixar, he helped to make Disney Animation Studio creative again while keeping their personality and not becoming another Pixar. This book is unique because it talks about creativity in an industry with high technical constraints. When Pixar created Toy Story, it was the first 3D animated movie, and most of their first movies were a cutting-edge technology developed to tell new and compelling stories. Also, as most of the books when you learn about the creativity of a company, Catmull detail a lot how his behavior and the behavior of his teams were the keys to a creative mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you give a good idea to a mediocre team, they will screw it up. If you give a mediocre idea to a brilliant team, they will either fix it or throw it away and come up with something better. The takeaway here is worth repeating: Getting the team right is the necessary precursor to getting the ideas right.
&lt;small&gt;Catmull, Ed. Creativity, Inc.: Overcoming the Unseen Forces That Stand in the Way of True Inspiration&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;orbiting-the-giant-hairball-a-corporate-fool-s-guide-to-surviving-with-grace-https-www-goodreads-com-book-show-100469-orbiting-the-giant-hairball&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/100469.Orbiting_the_Giant_Hairball&#34;&gt;Orbiting the Giant Hairball: A Corporate Fool&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Surviving with Grace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-hairball.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:200px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is the other side of the creativity spectrum in businesses. Gordon McKenzie worked at Hallmark Cards for 30 years. At one point, as he can tell, nobody knew what exactly his job was, so he took the title &lt;em&gt;creative paradox&lt;/em&gt; and started receiving calls from an employee about new ideas to have a sort of agreement. He always said &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;. This beautiful, messy and original book tells the story of a creative mind orbiting around the giant hairball that was becoming more and more his company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-hairball-example.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Orbiting the Giant Hairball&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-making-mistakes-https-www-goodreads-com-book-show-41732061-the-art-of-making-mistakes-ac-1-from-search-true&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41732061-the-art-of-making-mistakes?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&#34;&gt;The Art of Making Mistakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-mistakes.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:200px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As every book about creativity will tell, mistakes are at the heart of inspiration, that why we are not comfortable with it. This book is a compilation of 13 essays on mistakes, on how theater people deal with them and include them in their life. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have a better way of approaching the subject: by having 13 voices, we learn about mistakes with very different points of views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;oh my God, it&amp;rsquo;s my turn.
The lights up and they point straight at me.
Everybody is watching me.
I&amp;rsquo;m being blinded; I feel dizzy, sweaty; my shoulders are tensing up;
I&amp;rsquo;m feeling a lump in my throat, thirsty; my mouth is drying up; my heart is pounding, hands are shaking;
I&amp;rsquo;m feeling out of breath; I can&amp;rsquo;t breathe&amp;hellip;
How do I get out?
Can I still cancel the whole thing?
What was I supposed to say? What if I&amp;rsquo;m not funny?
What if I say something wrong?
What if nobody likes me?
What if I fall, mess up?
&lt;small&gt;Marianna Räsänen in The Art of Making Mistakes&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To know more about this book, you can check &lt;a href=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/the-art-of-making-mistakes-book-review/&#34;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hitchhiker-s-guide-to-the-galaxy-https-www-goodreads-com-book-show-13-the-ultimate-hitchhiker-s-guide-to-the-galaxy-ac-1-from-search-true&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13.The_Ultimate_Hitchhiker_s_Guide_to_the_Galaxy?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&#34;&gt;Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-h2g2.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:200px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably already know this title as it&amp;rsquo;s the famous Science Fiction trilogy in five books by Douglas Adams. This book is on this list because it&amp;rsquo;s for me a perfect example of creativity. It&amp;rsquo;s not the invention of a whole new world as can be some fantasy or science fiction books. It&amp;rsquo;s the crazy mind of Douglas Adams taking a look on our society, his authentic look. The quote below is one of my favorite examples. A lot of Science Fiction books imagine crazy technology to makes ships invisible, Douglas Adams didn&amp;rsquo;t, he just took an everyday event we all experienced where our things became invisible and applied it to a spaceship!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Somebody Else&amp;rsquo;s Problem field is much simpler and more effective, and what&amp;rsquo;s more can be run for over a hundred years on a single torch battery. This is because it relies on people&amp;rsquo;s natural disposition not to see anything they don&amp;rsquo;t want to, weren&amp;rsquo;t expecting, or can&amp;rsquo;t explain.
&lt;small&gt;Douglas Adams in Life, the Universe and Everything (H2G2 #3)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;magical-mathematics-https-www-goodreads-com-book-show-11505711-magical-mathematics-ac-1-from-search-true&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11505711-magical-mathematics?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&#34;&gt;Magical Mathematics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-diaconis-magic.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:200px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To finish a math book but don&amp;rsquo;t run away, it&amp;rsquo;s also a magic book. Persi Diaconis is a Statistician and a Magician. This book presents the math behind some magic tricks. It is an excellent example of creativity because this type of magic is a perfect mix of art and science. You discover a mathematical theorem, how to create a story around to make it a fantastic trick. Many magic tricks are based on the same theorems but feel different. With this book, you discover that you can change your view to make a boring mathematical theorem become the most impressive magic you&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. Don&amp;rsquo;t take me wrong; this is a book with a lot of math if you only want to learn magic tricks, pick another one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the problems in juggling is that gravity is inconveniently strong on the Earth. It has been estimated that a seven-ball juggler on the Earth could juggle forty-one balls on the moon (which has gravity one-sixth as strong as the Earth), except for certain practical difficulties, such as being in a spacesuit and the fact that the pattern doesn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;scale,&amp;rdquo; i.e., if you throw a forty-one-ball pattern forty feet up, you have to be very accurate since the spread between your two hands is still only (at most) six feet.
&lt;small&gt;Diaconis, Persi. Magical Mathematics: The Mathematical Ideas That Animate Great Magic Tricks&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/horizontal-slim-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; width:100%;}
   
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://theworldasastage.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b&amp;amp;id=32885e90b3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
    Subscribe to the newsletter to receive new book recommendations every week.
  &lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34; placeholder=&#34;email address&#34; required&gt;
    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b_32885e90b3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;books&#34; name=&#34;SIGNUPWHY&#34; class=&#34;required&#34; id=&#34;mce-SIGNUPWHY&#34;&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The art of Making Mistakes, book review</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/the-art-of-making-mistakes-book-review/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/the-art-of-making-mistakes-book-review/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;As a Chief Technical Officer, I see my job as trying to notice as fast as possible our new mistakes and adapt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in an unknown environment with new technologies, avoiding mistakes is impossible. We do mistakes, all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything fails all the time.
&lt;small&gt;Werner Vogels, CTO of Amazon Web Services&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, even in this environment, we can be sometimes scared to try something new because of the fear of failure, this is a human reflex that probably helped our ancestor to survive while dangerous animals ate more risky individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I found the book &amp;ldquo;The art of making mistakes&amp;rdquo; with 13 short essays on mistakes by improviser or theater people, I could not wait to read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;patti-stiles-and-mistakes-as-a-learning-process&#34;&gt;Patti Stiles and mistakes as a learning process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patti Stiles is one of the most incredible improvisation teachers I&amp;rsquo;ve met so far. Even if you improvised before and she is flying from Australia in your region, book a place, you won&amp;rsquo;t regret it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She writes the introduction to this book. She shares how Keith Johnstone, since the first day, permitted her to make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One night I was operating lights for the show Theatersports. It was my first time in the booth and I was taking everything very seriously, making sure I knew the correct sequences and controls. I was terrified of making a mistake, destroying the show and letting everyone down. Keith came into the lighting booth, casually looking around, asking, &amp;ldquo;Is this your first time doing lights?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo; I replied
&amp;ldquo;Ah&amp;rdquo;, he said. &amp;ldquo;You need to make at least 3 mistakes or you haven&amp;rsquo;t done your job.
Then he left the booth.
For the whole show I was looking for any opportunity to take risks so that I could make my quota of mistakes. At the end of the show he said, &amp;ldquo;Patti, you made 2 mistakes  try again next time.&amp;rdquo;
Keith used the logic of success to get me to make mistakes. He relieved me of the stress of fear of failure by giving me permission to make mistakes. He created an environment where I could take risk and learn.
&lt;small&gt;Patti Stiles&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach was very different from everything she experienced at school (and that you probably experienced too). We are so used to give negative feedback that we don&amp;rsquo;t even notice it anymore. In some countries it has also become a way of providing some respect, Frenchs uses the expression &amp;ldquo;Qui aime bien chatie bien&amp;rdquo; (literally who likes you, criticizes you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During Patti Stiles Loose Moose improvisation education as she describes it, mistakes were not only tolerated, it was considered as an indispensable need of the learning process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paolo-busi-on-diversity-and-difference&#34;&gt;Paolo Busi on diversity and difference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paolo Busi is an italian actor and director. He created Impromask, an improvised mask show with Commedia Dell&amp;rsquo;Arte influences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a teacher, my first task is to suspend judgment. As an improv teacher, the second one is to help the students suspend judgment on themselves
&lt;small&gt;Paolo Busi&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paolo Busi insists on how &lt;em&gt;tolerate diversity and originality&lt;/em&gt; is different from &lt;em&gt;accepting differences and uniqueness of every individuals&lt;/em&gt;. For Paolo Busi, in a &lt;em&gt;difference&lt;/em&gt; environent, we judge others: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;He is original, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow the rules&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. In a &lt;em&gt;diversity&lt;/em&gt; environment we suspend judgment&amp;rdquo;_ His ideas are different from mine, what can I learn?_.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mistake appear when I judge some action — mine or someone else’s — as wrong. As long as I can reframe the situation, to integrate what is happening into what was already there, mistakes do not exist.
&lt;small&gt;Paolo Busi&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suspension of judgment is a crucial element of communication and creativity. Also, as soon you accept that a mistake does not exist before judgment, a full room of possibilities appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of improvisation with the same group, I thought I was a good improviser. However, when, at an audition, I had to improvise with a beginner, I was shocked at how helpless I was when the improviser does not share the same set of &lt;em&gt;good practices&lt;/em&gt;. They were making a lot of &lt;em&gt;mistakes&lt;/em&gt; which blocked me to push the story forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scene is at the market, we are selling fruits next to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: &amp;ldquo;We had more people last week, I wonder where they all are?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: &amp;ldquo;Who are you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most natural path is to think that this answer is a mistake: We are selling fruits next to each other, I talk to her as if we knew each other and had this casual discussion of the number of people, her answer does not have a direct connexion to what I said&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, she this is her offer, and it&amp;rsquo;s improvisation, you can&amp;rsquo;t be a good improviser if you only react well each time everything happens as planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if it was not a mistake? What can explain that she can&amp;rsquo;t recognize me? Maybe she had an accident and lost her memory. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s the twin brother of my friend. Perhaps I have a memory problem, and I think I know this person, Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m a  compulsive seducer and that is my catchphrase. Perhaps nobody was in the market because of an alien invasion yesterday, and every human but me is parasitized by an alien.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just by considering that this &lt;em&gt;mistake&lt;/em&gt; was an &lt;em&gt;offer&lt;/em&gt;, an endless number of possibilities develop. And they seem way more intriging than the initial casual discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;anna-lena-østern-and-the-self-judgment&#34;&gt;Anna-Lena Østern and the self-judgment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anna-Lena Østern is one of the pioneers of drama education in Finland. She shares in this book personal thoughts and feelings about mistakes and our love-hate relationship with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the mistakes I can recall, though, have a feeling of shame attached to them. Something connected to not being observant enough, not being understanding enough, and sometimes being too naive, or not being authentic or true to myself, not listening to my gut feeling, or simply trying to be something I am not in order to please.
&lt;small&gt;Anna-Lena Østern&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to read more and learn about mistakes, I highly recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://draamatyo.fi/tuote/the-art-of-making-mistakes/&#34;&gt;grabbing this book&lt;/a&gt;. All the texts are unique and give a new point of view on this very particular subject.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/horizontal-slim-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; width:100%;}
   
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://theworldasastage.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b&amp;amp;id=32885e90b3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
    Subscribe to the newsletter to receive new book recommendations every week.
  &lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34; placeholder=&#34;email address&#34; required&gt;
    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b_32885e90b3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;books&#34; name=&#34;SIGNUPWHY&#34; class=&#34;required&#34; id=&#34;mce-SIGNUPWHY&#34;&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>5 great books about acting</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/5-great-books-about-acting/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/5-great-books-about-acting/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here are 5 excellent books about acting. More than being only to learn how to acts, these books explore human behaviors and how to bring these behaviors on stage. Also, if you don&amp;rsquo;t perform, since &lt;a href=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/team-collaboration-is-hard-improvisation-training-can-help/&#34;&gt;improvisation is anywhere there is human communication&lt;/a&gt; you would be surprised how much you can learn from them.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/horizontal-slim-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; width:100%;}
   
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://theworldasastage.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b&amp;amp;id=32885e90b3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
    Subscribe to my newsletter to receive one new book recommendation every week.
  &lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34; placeholder=&#34;email address&#34; required&gt;
    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b_32885e90b3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;books&#34; name=&#34;SIGNUPWHY&#34; class=&#34;required&#34; id=&#34;mce-SIGNUPWHY&#34;&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h2 id=&#34;audition-everything-an-actor-needs-to-know-to-get-the-part-https-www-goodreads-com-book-show-787895-audition&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/787895.Audition&#34;&gt;Audition: Everything an Actor Needs to Know to Get the Part&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-audition.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:200px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Shurtleff has been casting director for Broadway, and this is his book on advice on how to succeed at an audition. I was surprised when I first read it how most of his advice goes way beyond the theater world. They are useful for improv of course but also to understand and be more present in our day to day relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;allow anything to be possible ; make choices that give you the maximum possible involvement . If there&amp;rsquo;s a possibility , however unlikely , however remote , that you might love the other character in the scene , say yes to the possibility . There&amp;rsquo;s more feeling in potential love than there is in the impossibility of it . Feeling is what an actor is looking for ; why not pick the most ?
&lt;small&gt;Shurtleff, Michael. Audition: Everything an Actor Needs to Know to Get the Part&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;respect-for-acting-https-www-goodreads-com-book-show-140502-respect-for-acting&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/140502.Respect_for_Acting&#34;&gt;Respect for Acting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-respect-for-acting.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:200px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uta Hagen is a well-known actress. Her book has a strong connexion with Audition, but it&amp;rsquo;s written from the point of view of an actress instead of a director. She gives much valuable advice on how to be more present on stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The continuing job of learning to find out who you really are, of learning to pinpoint your responses and even more important, the myriad, consequent behaviorisms which result will help you begin to fill your warehouse with sources upon which to draw for the construction of a character (the new you selected for your character on stage).
&lt;small&gt;Uta Hagen, Respect for Acting&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-great-acting-teachers-and-their-methods-https-www-goodreads-com-book-show-237165-the-great-acting-teachers-and-their-methods-career-development-series&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/237165.The_Great_Acting_Teachers_and_Their_Methods_Career_Development_Series_&#34;&gt;The Great Acting Teachers and Their Methods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-acting-teachers.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:200px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book introduces several great acting teachers and describes their methods and their influence on the history of acting. It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to understand better modern acting as all these teachers have influenced it. It&amp;rsquo;s also a fantastic way to find very different approaches on the job of acting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The art of acting has not taught the world to lie . People have done so since the beginning of time . And if acting in a play is lying , then we simply do not see that lie as destructive . Rather , we regard that lie as Picasso defined all of art , as &amp;ldquo;the lie that reveals a deeper truth .&amp;rdquo;
&lt;small&gt;Brestoff, Richard. Great Acting Teachers and Their Methods&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-actor-s-trick-https-www-goodreads-com-book-show-1570409-an-actor-s-tricks&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1570409.An_Actor_s_Tricks&#34;&gt;An Actor&amp;rsquo;s trick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-an-actor-trick.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:200px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oriental and Western theater have influenced Yoshi Oida. This book has a very different tone than most American inspired acting books. Instead of trying to describe a method, he presents his way of acting as an example and proposes to learn by experimenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A true teacher never explains, never gives out recipes. He - or sometimes she - is a living example of what is possible, of what can be achieved with endless patience and unshakeable determination.
&lt;small&gt;Yoishi Oida - An Actor&amp;rsquo;s Tricks (Performance Books)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;free-play-improvisation-in-life-and-art-https-www-goodreads-com-book-show-9386-free-play-ac-1-from-search-true&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9386.Free_Play?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&#34;&gt;Free Play: Improvisation in Life and Art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/book-free-play.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:200px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last book is not an acting book. Stephen Nachmanovitch writes about the creative process. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken my time to read this book since each chapter is an opportunity to think about one aspect of creativity. Also, as an improviser, spontaneous creation is part of the process, so this book is not far from acting. Just give it a try, chapter by chapter, it&amp;rsquo;s worth the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We disappear and become a carrier wave, a vehicle for the music that plays us. The power of creative spontaneity develops into an explosion that liberates us from outmoded frames of reference and from memory that is clogged with old facts and old feelings. Addiction, procrastination, and fear are blown away by this carrier wave, and our music becomes a message about big Self .
&lt;small&gt;Nachmanovitch, Stephen. Free Play: Improvisation in Life and Art&lt;/small&gt;

&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/horizontal-slim-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; width:100%;}
   
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://theworldasastage.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b&amp;amp;id=32885e90b3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
    Subscribe to the newsletter to receive new book recommendations every week.
  &lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34; placeholder=&#34;email address&#34; required&gt;
    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b_32885e90b3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;books&#34; name=&#34;SIGNUPWHY&#34; class=&#34;required&#34; id=&#34;mce-SIGNUPWHY&#34;&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    </channel>
</rss>