<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
    <title>Management on The world as a stage</title>
    <link>http://theworldasastage.com/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on The world as a stage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://theworldasastage.com/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
        <title>Two questions at the Applied Improvisation Network Conference</title>
        <link>http://theworldasastage.com/two-questions-at-the-applied-improvisation-network-conference/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://theworldasastage.com/two-questions-at-the-applied-improvisation-network-conference/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Between August 23rd and 26th 2018, Paris is hosting the &lt;a href=&#34;http://appliedimprovisation.network&#34;&gt;Applied Improvisation Network conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Applied Improvisation&amp;rdquo; consists in using theatre improvisation outside of the theatre space to foster the development of creating teams, better communication and a lot of other qualities a good improviser tend to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://appliedimprovisation.network&#34;&gt;Applied Improvisation Network&lt;/a&gt; is a community of more than 5000 members online. This conference is the opportunity for improvisers applying their passion in a lot of various fields to share how to bring the improviser mindset outside of the stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time this year, I will attend this event. Since &lt;a href=&#34;http://podcastscience.fm&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m used to doing podcasts&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll bring my mic to the conference and record the answers of the attendees to these two questions. You can listen to the lastest episode below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.pippa.io/5b793e715d32cfd871dc6e9c?theme=default&amp;cover=1&amp;latest=1&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;218px&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When did you discover applied improvisation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered the official term &amp;ldquo;applied improvisation&amp;rdquo; two years after actually applying improvisation outside of the theatre. It seemed evident that other people were seeing links between the work of improvisation and what is needed in a business setting but I could not imagine that such a network as the Applied Improvisation Network existed. While I was starting to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://improwiki.com/en/wiki/improv/status&#34;&gt;status&lt;/a&gt; and word association games in meetings, I started looking for books and community working on the same topics and discovered the &lt;a href=&#34;http://appliedimprovisation.network/library/books-articles/&#34;&gt;vast library of the AIN&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to applied improv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some attendees of the conference, like &lt;a href=&#34;http://appliedimprovisation.network/practitioner/paul-z-jackson/&#34;&gt;Paul Z. Jackson&lt;/a&gt;, used applied improvisation for 20 years. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that they have exciting stories about their first experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What example of applied improvisation are you the proudest of?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bringing improvisation games to non-improvisers is always a challenge. The first time I tried a game with my team before a creative session, (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dramaresource.com/one-word-at-a-time/&#34;&gt;One word at a time&lt;/a&gt;)  the reaction was variable. Some were very excited where others were happy it was not too long. But all gave me the feedback that this game helped them be more open for the creative work and see the concept of &lt;em&gt;listening&lt;/em&gt; with a new dimension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is only a little example from a &lt;em&gt;amateur&lt;/em&gt; improviser experimenting. A lot of participants of the conference are improving their application of theater techniques since years and have created full workshops to achieve a particular goal. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine the examples they will tell.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/horizontal-slim-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; width:100%;}
   
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://theworldasastage.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b&amp;amp;id=32885e90b3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
    Subscribe to receive a mail for each new podcast and know more about applied improvisation.
  &lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34; placeholder=&#34;email address&#34; required&gt;
    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b_32885e90b3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll meet at the conference, or perhaps you can&amp;rsquo;t make it this year. Anyway, you can still start by answering these two little questions in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    </channel>
</rss>