<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
    <title>Warmup on The world as a stage</title>
    <link>https://theworldasastage.com/tags/warmup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Warmup on The world as a stage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://theworldasastage.com/tags/warmup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
        <title>Mind meld</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/warmup/mindmeld/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/warmup/mindmeld/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a group, a first player says &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt; when he thinks of a word. Then when a second player thinks he knows the word of the first player he says &lt;em&gt;2&lt;/em&gt;. Finally together they say &lt;em&gt;1,2,3&lt;/em&gt; and their world. If they have the same word, it&amp;rsquo;s a Mind Meld!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good warmup to put a group in the same energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group size :&lt;/strong&gt; From 4 people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; : 5-10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a lot to precise, just describe the game and start it.
When there is a &lt;em&gt;Mind Meld&lt;/em&gt;, the players must dance and sing :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a mind meld! It&amp;rsquo;s a mind meld! It happens all the time, it&amp;rsquo;s a mind meld!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remarks&#34;&gt;Remarks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The description of the game may sound impossible but by playing it, improvisers discover that each new word is a cue to find the next word association.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Zip, Zap, Zop</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/warmup/zipzapzop/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/warmup/zipzapzop/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a circle participants pass a &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt; noise to each other. One player can decide to say &lt;em&gt;Zap!&lt;/em&gt; to change the direction of the noise or to say &lt;em&gt;Zop!&lt;/em&gt; to skip the next player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game is perfect to make every member of the group present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group size :&lt;/strong&gt; From 4 people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; : 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask the participants to form a circle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start by showing : say &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt; and do a hand gesture to &amp;ldquo;give the noise&amp;rdquo; to the player on your right. If he doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow naturally explain to repeat and pass to his right neighbour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After two turn in the same direction, introduce &lt;em&gt;Zap!&lt;/em&gt; with the gesture of crossing your arms. When a player recieve a &lt;em&gt;Zap!&lt;/em&gt; on his &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt;, the sense of transmission change, he needs to pass the &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt; to the other direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After some time with &lt;em&gt;Zap!&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt;, introduce finally the &lt;em&gt;Zop!&lt;/em&gt; : when a player says &lt;em&gt;Zop!&lt;/em&gt;, he needs to put his two hands as if he was wearing googles. The player next to him is skipped and the game continue in the same direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remarks&#34;&gt;Remarks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the game become more easy for participants, ask to go faster. And also to take more risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time, we can introduce new rules (without describing them, just by showing) and some player should repeat the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    </channel>
</rss>