<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
    <title>Podcast on The world as a stage</title>
    <link>https://theworldasastage.com/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on The world as a stage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://theworldasastage.com/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
        <title>Tutorial : How to host, record and broadcast a podcast with distributed members</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/tutorial--how-to-host-record-and-broadcast-a-podcast-with-distributed-members/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/tutorial--how-to-host-record-and-broadcast-a-podcast-with-distributed-members/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&#34;http://podcastscience.fm&#34;&gt;Podcast Science&lt;/a&gt;, I host, record and broadcast a popular science podcast in French every week since 2010. We had a lot of trial and error to establish a setup that allowed us to :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host and record a podcast with participants in different places (we have people every week from France, Switzerland, Spain and US)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broadcast it live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play sounds and jingles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a fully detailed step-by-step tutorial with animated gif on how to setup your computer to make it a real live podcast studio!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuration&#34;&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use our setup you must use a &lt;strong&gt;Mac&lt;/strong&gt; since we couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any equivalents of the main softwares we need. You need to get the following softwares (they all have a trial version) :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rogueamoeba.com/audiohijack/&#34;&gt;Audio Hijack&lt;/a&gt; (59$) to do about everything, this is &lt;em&gt;THE&lt;/em&gt; mandatory element of our setup. This software is awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rogueamoeba.com/loopback/&#34;&gt;Loopback&lt;/a&gt; ( 99$ ) to be able to connect audio as you want, this is also mandatory and I don&amp;rsquo;t know any free equivalent (&lt;a href=&#34;https://rogueamoeba.com/freebies/soundflower/&#34;&gt;Soundflower&lt;/a&gt; was doing the job for free but seems dead).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://skype.com&#34;&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt; (0$ ) or any other audio communication tool like &lt;a href=&#34;https://discordapp.com/&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; (0$ ) , &lt;a href=&#34;https://appear.in&#34;&gt;Appear&lt;/a&gt; (0$ ), etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rogueamoeba.com/farrago/&#34;&gt;Farrago&lt;/a&gt; (39$ ) to play jingles. You can also use any other software that can play a sound like &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/&#34;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; (0$ ) or &lt;a href=&#34;http://spotify.com&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; (0$ )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed, all the paid applications we use come from Rogue Amoeba, in our experience these app are the most reliable we&amp;rsquo;ve found (and you&amp;rsquo;ll hate to have a technical problem when you start your live podcast&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so if you want several of them you can buy bundles :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio Hijack and Loopback bundle for 130$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Ultimate Podcast Bundle for 170$ (with another app called Fission which is perfect to edit the meta data of a MP3 before posting it on your feed).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also need a Mic. For one person, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Zoom-H2N-H2n-Handy-Recorder/dp/B005CQ2ZY6?keywords=zoom+H2&amp;amp;qid=1536820944&amp;amp;s=Musical+Instruments&amp;amp;sr=1-4&amp;amp;ref=sr_1_4&#34;&gt;Zoom H2N&lt;/a&gt; (170$ ) or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Blue-Yeti-USB-Microphone-Blackout/dp/B00N1YPXW2?keywords=yeti+blue&amp;amp;qid=1536820897&amp;amp;sr=8-5&amp;amp;ref=sr_1_5&#34;&gt;Blue Yeti&lt;/a&gt; (130$, often discounted on Amazon) are very good options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hosting-and-recording&#34;&gt;Hosting and recording&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to make the podcast happen : to be able to talk to other folks and to record the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are alone in your podcast, there are a lot of easier configurations but the one I&amp;rsquo;m presenting here will allow you to do much more :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will be able to host a podcast with several people (at your home or online)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will be able to play jingles (next part)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will be able to broadcast (last part)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll use Audio Hijack and our objective is to create a configuration similar to the one below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll have one or several mics (1) that we will record in different files (2). All these voices will be sent in Skype (3) so that the other podcast member online we hear us. We&amp;rsquo;ll get the voice of the other people through Skype to record it (4) and finally make us able to hear them (5).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio Hijack allows you to do all that almost as easily as the figure. First open the software and go to &lt;code&gt;Session &amp;gt; New Session&lt;/code&gt; (Cmd+N). You will have a new window asking for the kind of Session you want to create, pick &amp;ldquo;New Blank Session&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we&amp;rsquo;ll add the mics (1 in the figure). To do that click open the source library (by clicking on &amp;ldquo;show library&amp;rdquo; if it&amp;rsquo;s closed). Pick the source &amp;ldquo;Input device&amp;rdquo;, click and drag it anywhere in the main window as in the gif below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-3.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have to configure your source to connect it to your mic. Click on the mic you just added to make the menu &amp;ldquo;Audio Source&amp;rdquo; appear. If you use the internal mic of your Mac, no more configuration to do. But if you use a more complex mic you should open the &amp;ldquo;Advanced&amp;rdquo; part on the menu to select which sources you exactly want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the same method to add as many inputs as you need for each mic you have. In this example I have two inputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we need a recorder to record our audio. As for the input, click and drag on the recorder to add it on the main window and connect the &amp;ldquo;Recorders&amp;rdquo; to the inputs as presented in the gif.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-6.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be very careful that, as in the example, your recorders are connected to only &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; input. The connexion is the little &amp;ldquo;tube&amp;rdquo; between the square elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-7.png&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you need to configure your recorder. As for the input device, click on each recorder element to configure it. If you plan on editing your podcast, don&amp;rsquo;t pick MP3 for the format as it&amp;rsquo;s compressed. At PodcastScience, our recorders have the following configuration :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality : custom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Format : Wav&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type : 24bits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample Rate : Auto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Channels : Mono (our mics are mono, if yours are stereo, pick stereo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The configuration process is illustrated by the gif below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-8.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now we have mics that we record (yay!), we still have to send this voices to skype so your friends can hear you. In an ideal world, we should be able to open Skype and pick &amp;ldquo;Audio Hijack&amp;rdquo; as a source but this is impossible&amp;hellip; Here come the need of Loopback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as you installed Loopback, you should have a new window open, &lt;strong&gt;you have nothing to configure here&lt;/strong&gt;, close it and go back to Audio Hijack. Loopback is like a virtual cable, so instead of connecting directly Audio Hijack to Skype you do it through Loopback : You first connect Audio Hijack to Loopback and then Loopback to Skype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Audio Hijack, add an &amp;ldquo;Output Device&amp;rdquo; to the main window. Move it so that it&amp;rsquo;s connected to all your inputs&amp;rsquo; recorders. Then click on it to configure it and pick &amp;ldquo;Loopback Audio&amp;rdquo;. All this is presented in the gif below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-9.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No you need to be sure that Skype uses this new input. You have to go in the preference panel of Skype and pick &amp;ldquo;Loopback audio&amp;rdquo; as the input. I don&amp;rsquo;t put any capture of Skype interface in this post since Skype loves to change its interface every other month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Test!&lt;/strong&gt; Your configuration is not finished but you can start testing it : Talk with our mic and check if someone you call on Skype can hear you and that you get a record (and if you are alone you can call the Skype test call). To do that, click on the red button (&lt;strong&gt;As long as you don&amp;rsquo;t click the red button, nothing will be recorded and you won&amp;rsquo;t be heard&lt;/strong&gt;) and then call your friend on Skype. You should see the &amp;ldquo;tubes&amp;rdquo; on Audio Hijack become orange as you speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-10.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your friend can hear you, this is good news (be sure he hear you from the mic you want to test).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s check the recorded files. To find them, click on &amp;ldquo;Recordings,&amp;rdquo; then
&amp;ldquo;Actions&amp;rdquo; and finally &amp;ldquo;Reveal in Finder&amp;rdquo; to open a Finder window on the folder of your recordings. You should have one file per recorder. If you can find the find and hear your voice, that&amp;rsquo;s a win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-11.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still need to record the voice of the people on Skype. To do that we&amp;rsquo;ll build a parallel configuration on the same Audio Hijack window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the source library, pick &amp;ldquo;Application&amp;rdquo; and drag it to the main window &lt;strong&gt;without connecting it to anything&lt;/strong&gt;. Click on it and pick &amp;ldquo;Skype.&amp;rdquo; In &amp;ldquo;Advanced,&amp;rdquo; uncheck &amp;ldquo;Include Audio Input&amp;rdquo; (You already record the audio input so you don&amp;rsquo;t need it a second time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-12.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need now to add a &amp;ldquo;Recorder&amp;rdquo; (with the same config as before) to record what comes from Skype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you stop here, you won&amp;rsquo;t hear anything anymore on Skype because Audio Hijack captures the sound of Skype. You have to add a new &amp;ldquo;Output Device&amp;rdquo; with your headset to get the output again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-13.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your setup is complete! You can test it by pushing the red button and calling someone. All the &amp;ldquo;tubes&amp;rdquo; should become orange as people speak and you should find all the recorded files at the end of the call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-14.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the link between the initial figure and your configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-15.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jingles&#34;&gt;Jingles!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be able to play sounds in a configuration like Podcast Science (several people in different places) with only one computer is way more complicated than it seems. However, hopefully, Audio Hijack makes this smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main issue is that we want the sounds to be heard by us &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the other people on Skype. Moreover, we don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear our own voice in the mic (which is also a Skype input). So we&amp;rsquo;ll have to add the sounds in our setup twice: once for us, and once for the people remote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can play your jingles from any app; I&amp;rsquo;ll use Farrago because it&amp;rsquo;s a very convenient tool to play quick sounds when you need them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in Audio Hijack, you&amp;rsquo;ll create two &amp;ldquo;Application&amp;rdquo; sources :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the first one connects to Loopback (to go in Skype)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the second one connects to our headset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I don&amp;rsquo;t connect Farrago to the recorders since I don&amp;rsquo;t want to record them, I&amp;rsquo;ll add them directly in the editing for better sound quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-16.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have two &amp;ldquo;Farrago&amp;rdquo; boxes, but they represent the same application, this is where the magic of Audio Hijack occurs. If you play a sound and start recording, you should see the tubes become orange again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-17.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You may have one of the two blocs that stop working when you start Audio Hijack. Just delete it (right click and delete) and create a new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now you can play sounds during your podcast! You can use the same methods to add sources that only you and/or other people can hear. For example, at Podcast Science, I can monitor our live broadcast when I need by connecting Google Chrome as an input of my headset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our final configuration (without broadcast) for Podcast Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-18.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-broadcast&#34;&gt;Live broadcast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last and easiest step: Live Broadcast. Audio Hijack (still him) can also manage the broadcast as soon as you use a &lt;a href=&#34;http://icecast.org/&#34;&gt;Icecast&lt;/a&gt; (We rent ours on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infomaniak.com/fr&#34;&gt;Infomaniak&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a broadcast to your configuration, you need to add a new &amp;ldquo;Skype Application&amp;rdquo; block and a &amp;ldquo;Broadcast&amp;rdquo; block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/podcast/tutorial-19.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You then have to configure these two blocks. For Skype, no configuration should be required (be sure that &amp;ldquo;include audio input&amp;rdquo; is checked under the advanced panel). On the broadcast block, your configuration depends on your Icecast server, only the setup part is very important, the metadata part is for display only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some options will still be similar :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port : 8000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encoding format : Custom

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Format : MP3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bit rate : 96kbps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bit rate mode : constant bitrate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample rate : 44100 Hz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Channels : Stereo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is it! You know how to host, record and broadcast a podcast. If you have any comments on this procedure, feel free to share them on the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/horizontal-slim-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; width:100%;}
   
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://theworldasastage.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b&amp;amp;id=32885e90b3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
    Subscribe to my newsletter to receive my next articles!
  &lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34; placeholder=&#34;email address&#34; required&gt;
    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b_32885e90b3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;podcast&#34; name=&#34;SIGNUPWHY&#34; class=&#34;required&#34; id=&#34;mce-SIGNUPWHY&#34;&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Creativity and programming languages</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/creativity-and-programming-languages/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/creativity-and-programming-languages/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;Since the second half of the 20th century, we know that every language in which we can write a Turing Machine is a language with which we can write every single possible algorithm ever possible to write. Another way to say it is that for many years we know that all the programming language are equivalent, no one is able of more than any other, end of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/dropmic.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Drop mic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, we could live happily in a world where every programmer is using the same language to talk to machines, but it&amp;rsquo;s entirely not the case. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_programming_languages&#34;&gt;According to Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, there are more than 700 languages (and with no doubt all programming language ever created is not on this page). And it&amp;rsquo;s only the &lt;em&gt;programming languages&lt;/em&gt;, we can add libraries that sometimes modify so much a programming language that you can&amp;rsquo;t recognize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/programminglang-timeline.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Timeline of programming languages&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming languages are actually the hidden place of considerable creativity. I love art, cinema, theater and it&amp;rsquo;s in this particular field that I&amp;rsquo;ve been the most surprised by all the new idea we can discover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t believe me, this post is for you, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to answer these three questions :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we still create new languages?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are they really different?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it a creative activity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ultimate-programming-language&#34;&gt;The ultimate programming language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ultimate programming language has been tried long ago, and it didn&amp;rsquo;t stop the creation of new ones. Every programmer has his favorite language so this is not to start a war, I&amp;rsquo;m talking of a &lt;em&gt;ultimate programming language&lt;/em&gt; as a perfect idea that the language &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lisp_(programming_language)&#34;&gt;LISP&lt;/a&gt; illustrate perfectly in my opinion. This language was born in 1958 and as so is one of the first programming language ever created (14 years before &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_C_Programming_Language&#34;&gt;C&lt;/a&gt; and 32 years before &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_(programming_language)&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; that you probably know for example). Its syntax is straightforward, parenthesis, functions arguments&amp;hellip; and that&amp;rsquo;s all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;arg1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;arg2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;arg3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People think LISP is an ultimate language because some of his core concepts come directly from the dreams of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace&#34;&gt;Ada Lovelace&lt;/a&gt;: There are no differences between the data (inputs of our algorithms) and the language in which we process these inputs (the code we write). To put it in another way, we can use this language to modify its own behavior and adapt it to every problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LISP, created in 1958 can not only do everything (you can code a Turing machine), but it is also possible to modify its syntax as you need to adapt to your problem. Why would we need new languages after this one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reasons that are very similar to why it is powerful: LISP is hard to read, hard to use, hard to master and not necessarily the most efficient language for every application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must not judge a programming language only by what it can do or by its efficiency to do it but also by its ability to communicate an idea, an algorithm, to a computer. And, as it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes forgotten, to describe these algorithms to others humans!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believing that we need only one programming language is like believing only one art form is sufficient to communicate any idea. It&amp;rsquo;s assuming we should stop making movies, tv shows, comics, music because we already have books and it&amp;rsquo;s good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-best-way&#34;&gt;The best way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/G%C3%B6del-Escher-Bach-Eternal-Golden/dp/0465026567/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534543794&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=godel+escher&#34;&gt;Godel, Escher &amp;amp; Bach&lt;/a&gt; is a famous book which tries to connect the mathematician Godel, the artist Escher and the musician Bach. In the introduction to the French version, written by the author, Douglas Hofstadter explains that this French version is not an inferior version, neither a copy of the original version that would have lost some concepts during the process. No, he worked with the translators to make the same book, but in French. He presents this version as another projection of his ideas and that probably by reading the two text (if ever you are fluent in the two languages) you would get closer to the impression he wanted to transmit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A book or any work of art is only the transmission, as good as possible of what was of a mind of an artist. And sometimes some bugs occur: When Sam Ramy presents his horror movie &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dtsK7skqk9U&#34;&gt;Evil Dead&lt;/a&gt; and the public laugh in some scenes where it was supposed to be scared, it&amp;rsquo;s a bug (that will be used a lot in the following episodes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many works of art appear nowadays in several formats, sometimes freely adapted. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Martian-Young-Readers-ANDY-WEIR/dp/1785034677/ref=sr_1_8?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534544231&amp;amp;sr=8-8&amp;amp;keywords=the+martian&#34;&gt;The Martian&lt;/a&gt; first a book is getting stressful and addictive as an audiobook when the main character is telling us, day by day what happened to him. And of course, the movie presents incredible sightseeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other works of art seem to be stuck to one specific format. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Flowers-Algernon-Daniel-Keyes/dp/015603008X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534544373&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=flowers+for+algernon&#34;&gt;Flowers for Algernon&lt;/a&gt;, we read the journal of a retarded person who is having treatment to enhance his IQ. At the beginning of the book the writing is very hard to follow, and as we turn the pages, the novel evolves with the narrator IQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some writers use their medium to the limit. As if limited by their own language, they invent a new one. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Horde-Contrevent-Sc-Fiction-French-ebook/dp/B01A6X03EI/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534544565&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=damasio+horde&#34;&gt;La horde du contrevent&lt;/a&gt;, Alain Damasio invents a syntax to describe the wind. With commas, parenthesis and other signs, we can see the wind move, hit and kill on the pages of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/img/horde.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;La horde du contrevent&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artists have in every epoch ask the question a programmer starts with: what is the best way to tell my story?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If programming were only about communicating to a computer, no programmer would invent a new syntax, a new language to describe what he is doing to his peers. A computer doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about that, it&amp;rsquo;s a machine after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;think-different&#34;&gt;Think different&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This far you must understand that there are several languages but, after all, what can make all these languages different? It&amp;rsquo;s still some cooking recipes, a list of instruction, some operation that we repeat, other done if some conditions are validated, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, of course, you can write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;condition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;action1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;();}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34; data-lang=&#34;ruby&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;action1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;condition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but it&amp;rsquo;s maybe not a reasonable justification for such a post&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the only differences between languages were this kind of small syntax changes, it would be pointless. But developers are way more creative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example: How to color a map with France, Belgium, Switzerland, and Germany with 3 colors (Red, Blue, Green) without having two adjacent regions with the same color?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing a &lt;em&gt;cooking recipe&lt;/em&gt; to solve this problem would be quite long as we would do what we are doing by hand: We try a color for the first country, use a différent one for the next one, etc. If at one point it&amp;rsquo;s impossible, we go back, and we change the colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to solve this problem is to use a &lt;em&gt;declarative language&lt;/em&gt;. For example, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prolog&#34;&gt;Prolog&lt;/a&gt;, we can write the following code  :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, we describe the fact that our colors are not the same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-prolog&#34; data-lang=&#34;prolog&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, we describe which are the neighboring countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-prolog&#34; data-lang=&#34;prolog&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;coloring&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;France&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Belgique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Suisse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Allemagne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;):-&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;France&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Belgique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;France&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Suisse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;France&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Allemagne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Belgique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Allemagne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Suisse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Allemagne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, we ask for the solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-prolog&#34; data-lang=&#34;prolog&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;coloring&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;France&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Belgique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Suisse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Allemagne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is the algorithm? That&amp;rsquo;s precisely what seems magic with this way of programming: the algorithm &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; the description of the problem! We call this kind of language &lt;em&gt;declarative&lt;/em&gt;, we declare some rules, and after that, we can ask questions. One of the most popular declarative languages is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SQL&#34;&gt;SQL&lt;/a&gt;, a language used by most of the databases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no restriction on how should work a programming language. The only limits are the programmers&amp;rsquo; imagination. For example in the programming language &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.haskell.org/&#34;&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt;, we can define infinite lists! Of course, a computer can&amp;rsquo;t display all the elements of the list and crash if we ask for it but the programming language is &lt;em&gt;lazy&lt;/em&gt;, as far as we don&amp;rsquo;t ask, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some programming languages are more exercises of style like the &lt;em&gt;Shakespeare Programming Language&lt;/em&gt; where we code as if we were writing a Shakespeare play. For example, this program writes &amp;ldquo;Hello World.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Romeo](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romeo &amp;quot;Romeo&amp;quot;), a young man with a remarkable patience.
[Juliet](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juliet &amp;quot;Juliet&amp;quot;), a likewise young woman of remarkable grace.
[Ophelia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ophelia &amp;quot;Ophelia&amp;quot;), a remarkable woman much in dispute with Hamlet.
[Hamlet](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prince_Hamlet &amp;quot;Prince Hamlet&amp;quot;), the flatterer of Andersen Insulting A/S.

Act I: Hamlet&#39;s insults and flattery.
Scene I: The insulting of Romeo.
[Enter Hamlet and Romeo]
Hamlet:
You lying stupid fatherless big smelly half-witted coward! You are as
stupid as the difference between a handsome rich brave hero and thyself!
Speak your mind!
You are as brave as the sum of your fat little stuffed misused dusty
old rotten codpiece and a beautiful fair warm peaceful sunny summer&#39;s
day. You are as healthy as the difference between the sum of the
sweetest reddest rose and my father and yourself! Speak your mind!
You are as cowardly as the sum of yourself and the difference
between a big mighty proud kingdom and a horse. Speak your mind.
Speak your mind!
[Exit Romeo]
Scene II: The praising of Juliet.
[Enter Juliet]
Hamlet:
Thou art as sweet as the sum of the sum of Romeo and his horse and his
black cat! Speak thy mind!
[Exit Juliet]
Scene III: The praising of Ophelia.
[Enter Ophelia]
Hamlet:
Thou art as lovely as the product of a large rural town and my amazing
bottomless embroidered purse. Speak thy mind!
Thou art as loving as the product of the bluest clearest sweetest sky
and the sum of a squirrel and a white horse. Thou art as beautiful as
the difference between Juliet and thyself. Speak thy mind!
[Exeunt Ophelia and Hamlet]

Act II: Behind Hamlet&#39;s back.
Scene I: Romeo and Juliet&#39;s conversation.
[Enter Romeo and Juliet]
Romeo:
Speak your mind. You are as worried as the sum of yourself and the
difference between my small smooth hamster and my nose. Speak your
mind!
Juliet:
Speak YOUR mind! You are as bad as Hamlet! You are as small as the
difference between the square of the difference between my little pony
and your big hairy hound and the cube of your sorry little
codpiece. Speak your mind!
[Exit Romeo]
Scene II: Juliet and Ophelia&#39;s conversation.
[Enter Ophelia]
Juliet:
Thou art as good as the quotient between Romeo and the sum of a small
furry animal and a leech. Speak your mind!
Ophelia:
Thou art as disgusting as the quotient between Romeo and twice the
difference between a mistletoe and an oozing infected blister! Speak
your mind!
[Exeunt]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as strange as it is, this language is powerful enough to write a Turing machine, and as a consequence, any algorithm can be written with it. Yes, Microsoft World can be written in Shakespeare Programming Language, and it would be quite impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;human-communication&#34;&gt;Human communication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of differences in programming languages as the previous one. And if you can find a lot of programming languages that&amp;rsquo;s partly because of these kinds of design choices. It even seems that some paradigms of programming languages have the same roots as the cultural differences in human communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Culture-Map-Breaking-Invisible-Boundaries/dp/1610392507/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534546316&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+culture+map&#34;&gt;The Culture Map&lt;/a&gt;, Erin Meyer presents 7 criteria to analyze cultural differences :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** communication:** is the context very important or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** feedback:** direct or indirect negative feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** leading:** egalitarian or hierarchical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** deciding:** consensual or top down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** trusting:** according to what is done or via our relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** disagreeing:** confrontation or avoiding confrontation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;time management:&lt;/strong&gt; linear or non-linear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These criteria seem to correspond also to essential programming designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, some libraries use a &lt;em&gt;high context&lt;/em&gt;. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://rubyonrails.org/&#34;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt;, only writing &lt;code&gt;has_many :friends&lt;/code&gt; in a file named &lt;code&gt;user.rb&lt;/code&gt; is enough for the tool to understand that we have a database named &lt;code&gt;Users&lt;/code&gt; and another one &lt;code&gt;Friends&lt;/code&gt; and that the database &lt;code&gt;Friends&lt;/code&gt; will store a reference to the &lt;code&gt;Users&lt;/code&gt; database for each entry. So with only a small line of code, we avoid lines of descriptions. And as human communication, this kind of high context suppose that everyone is sharing the same context or some problems will occur quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to make feedback is also a severe difference between languages. &lt;em&gt;Variables&lt;/em&gt; have what we call a &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt;. For example &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; is an integer and &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; a string. Some programming languages are nice, you can write &lt;code&gt;1+&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; and the language will convert the string in an integer to do the sum. The other will be more strict and crash because they can&amp;rsquo;t add a string and an integer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More interesting even is the time management. As a cooking recipe, we can think as a programming language as a linear time algorithm where we do the operations line by line in order. But some languages start the next line without waiting for the previous one to finish, they are asynchronous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are only some examples of the differences between languages. Creating a language follow most of the time a need to communicate something in a particular way. We can find the same with books, some authors create a new world full of imaginary creatures to tell their story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is surprising with programming languages is that other people will use these weird creations and make it their primary tool, even if it requires a lot of adaptation. If very few worlds created by authors are used by others, for programming language it&amp;rsquo;s widespread. Most of the programmers can use several languages and adapt their choice to their needs. It&amp;rsquo;s as if a writer decided to use Italian to write his romance and switched to English for his thriller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;communicate-with-machines&#34;&gt;Communicate with machines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New languages are of course also created to make execution by machines more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the internet and the Web, it&amp;rsquo;s rarely only one computer which is processing the data but way more in parallel. As a consequence, these last years programming languages have been created to make this task easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a conclusion, there are a lot of programming languages, and there will probably be a lot more in the future. Because culture changes, because habits change because needs change, because it&amp;rsquo;s interesting, because it&amp;rsquo;s entertaining because it&amp;rsquo;s one of the ways humans have found to express their creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a translation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.podcastscience.fm/dossiers/2018/04/20/creativite-et-langages-de-programmation-2/&#34;&gt;Podcast Science 319&lt;/a&gt;, a weekly popular science podcast in french.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;références&#34;&gt;Références&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics#Computer_science&#34;&gt;A lot of different syntaxes to do the same thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_programming_languages&#34;&gt;Programming languages comparison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.fr/Seven-Languages-Weeks-Bruce-Tate/dp/193435659X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1524127105&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=seven+languages+in+seven+weeks&#34;&gt;Seven languages in seven weeks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    </channel>
</rss>