<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
    <title>Improv Game on The world as a stage</title>
    <link>https://theworldasastage.com/tags/improv-game/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Improv Game on The world as a stage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://theworldasastage.com/tags/improv-game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
        <title>Giving presents</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/exercises/presents/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/exercises/presents/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Player A offers an imaginary present to player B. Player B defines what is the present and show his happiness on what he has just been offered! The pair continues the same action back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game is very simple and very good to show how hard it can be to define what should be the easiest thing : a present we would like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group size :&lt;/strong&gt; By pairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; : 10-15 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the participants by pairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A presents B with an imaginary gift. A must offer the present so that B can see the shape of the present (is it big? is it squared, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B accepts with joy the present by defining it : &amp;ldquo;Oh! It&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;hellip;! Thank you!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then B gives a present to A and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remarks&#34;&gt;Remarks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If A is offering the present, it&amp;rsquo;s very important that it&amp;rsquo;s B and not A that should define the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A can offer very precise items or just a shape and let B define what is or what is inside this shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The participants should accepts the offer enthusiastically, it&amp;rsquo;s part of this exercice to accept any offer with the most positive attitude. You may advice the participant to start accepting the offer with joy and manipulating it even before they brain decided what it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The players should exchange more than 3 presents each to evacuate the first easy ideas they had in mind and become more spontaneous. You should encourage them to go fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;debrief-questions&#34;&gt;Debrief questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did it feel to recieve gifts? And to give them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did you think of having to identify the gift?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did it feel when the gift was identified as something else than what you offered?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does this relate to your work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this game because we ask a simple task : to define and be happy of a present we pick. Most of the time when we struggle finding ideas we thinj of a lot of exterior reasons : someone will juge us, we&amp;rsquo;ll look stupid, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the only juge is us and we realize how many stress we put on ourself. Why not just accepting the very good beer we are offering and looking for an unexpected present we won&amp;rsquo;t be that happy with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Offering a present is also an interesting experience since it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be an easy task. After all we just need to mime the offering of a present we don&amp;rsquo;t need to define. But we struggle the same :  we don&amp;rsquo;t want to offer the same shape, we want to define what is the present we are offering, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally you can also play this game in full connexion with the other person and make it playful and beautiful. What if this present was not only a good present but a good present that only your partner could have think of?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Mind meld</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/warmup/mindmeld/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/warmup/mindmeld/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a group, a first player says &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt; when he thinks of a word. Then when a second player thinks he knows the word of the first player he says &lt;em&gt;2&lt;/em&gt;. Finally together they say &lt;em&gt;1,2,3&lt;/em&gt; and their world. If they have the same word, it&amp;rsquo;s a Mind Meld!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good warmup to put a group in the same energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group size :&lt;/strong&gt; From 4 people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; : 5-10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a lot to precise, just describe the game and start it.
When there is a &lt;em&gt;Mind Meld&lt;/em&gt;, the players must dance and sing :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a mind meld! It&amp;rsquo;s a mind meld! It happens all the time, it&amp;rsquo;s a mind meld!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remarks&#34;&gt;Remarks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The description of the game may sound impossible but by playing it, improvisers discover that each new word is a cue to find the next word association.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>No / Yes but / Yes / Yes and</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/exercises/no-yesbut-yes-yesand/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/exercises/no-yesbut-yes-yesand/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;By pairs. Player A tells a story to player B. Player B can only answer &lt;em&gt;No&lt;/em&gt;. Then player B can only answer &lt;em&gt;Yes, But&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt; and finally &lt;em&gt;Yes, and&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good exercise to feel how we are affected by others&amp;rsquo; reaction to our ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group size :&lt;/strong&gt; By pairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; : 10-15 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the participants by pairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show an example with a participant. You start a story and this participant can only answer &lt;em&gt;No&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask the participants to do the same by Pair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After some time, ask them to switch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief this first session with the &lt;em&gt;No&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the same with the next answers : &lt;em&gt;Yes, but&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Yes And&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the whole exercice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A: Let&amp;rsquo;s go to the beach!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B: No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A: So let&amp;rsquo;s go to the mountain!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B: No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another one :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A: Let&amp;rsquo;s go to the beach!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B: Yes, but I can&amp;rsquo;t swim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A: So let&amp;rsquo;s just take the sun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B: Yes, but it gives cancer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remarks&#34;&gt;Remarks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let the stories continue some time before switching A and B. It&amp;rsquo;s part of the exercice to feel how hard it is to continue with some answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;debrief-questions&#34;&gt;Debrief questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between each answers :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does it feel to have only this as an answer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does it feel to start your sentences this way?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which was the more difficult, to answer or to build the story?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which answer did you prefer? In which role? Why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the link you see with the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As caricatural this exercise may sound, it&amp;rsquo;s a very efficient way to see how negative answers can be exhaustive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also interesting to see that with most groups, a &lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt; alone feel less good than a &lt;em&gt;Yes, but..&lt;/em&gt;. An interpretation is that to say &lt;em&gt;Yes, but&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; you have to not only listen (&lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;) but also to understand and build an answer connected (&lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt;). So you need to be more involved than a simple &lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exercise is also a good way to show how story can go farther when we build positively on them (&lt;em&gt;Yes, and&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>One sentence at a time</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/scenework/one-sentence-at-a-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/scenework/one-sentence-at-a-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two players do a scene. They must say one sentence at a time : Player A starts with a sentence, Player B answer with another sentence, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good setup to do scene where we concentrate on the listening between players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group size :&lt;/strong&gt; 2+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; : 30 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two players are doing a normal scene. Each player must say one sentence only and then listen to the answer by the other player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remarks&#34;&gt;Remarks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This setup help to analyse what is happening and how each players listen to each other. By saying one sentence at a time, you can discuss if each sentence is connected to the previous one and not blocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keith Johnstone in Impro for Storytellers presents a serie of way players are killing stories. This exercice is perfect to notice them and discuss with the group. Here are some of these blocking methods :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blocking : a direct negation to the offer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wimping : Accepting the ideas but don&amp;rsquo;t adding anything on them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancelling : demanteling what has been established&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gossiping : Avoiding interaction by discussing something that happen outside of the scene, arguing on a price, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agreed activities : Doing exactly what the other player ask you to do, killing all interaction that can exists between players.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidetracking : Adding elements to avoid the actual story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being original&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gagging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowering the stakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Zip, Zap, Zop</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/warmup/zipzapzop/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/warmup/zipzapzop/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a circle participants pass a &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt; noise to each other. One player can decide to say &lt;em&gt;Zap!&lt;/em&gt; to change the direction of the noise or to say &lt;em&gt;Zop!&lt;/em&gt; to skip the next player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game is perfect to make every member of the group present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group size :&lt;/strong&gt; From 4 people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt; : 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask the participants to form a circle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start by showing : say &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt; and do a hand gesture to &amp;ldquo;give the noise&amp;rdquo; to the player on your right. If he doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow naturally explain to repeat and pass to his right neighbour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After two turn in the same direction, introduce &lt;em&gt;Zap!&lt;/em&gt; with the gesture of crossing your arms. When a player recieve a &lt;em&gt;Zap!&lt;/em&gt; on his &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt;, the sense of transmission change, he needs to pass the &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt; to the other direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After some time with &lt;em&gt;Zap!&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt;, introduce finally the &lt;em&gt;Zop!&lt;/em&gt; : when a player says &lt;em&gt;Zop!&lt;/em&gt;, he needs to put his two hands as if he was wearing googles. The player next to him is skipped and the game continue in the same direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remarks&#34;&gt;Remarks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the game become more easy for participants, ask to go faster. And also to take more risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time, we can introduce new rules (without describing them, just by showing) and some player should repeat the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    </channel>
</rss>