<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
    <title>Posts on The world as a stage</title>
    <link>http://theworldasastage.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The world as a stage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://theworldasastage.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
        <title>Team collaboration is hard, Improvisation training can help</title>
        <link>http://theworldasastage.com/team-collaboration-is-hard-improvisation-training-can-help/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://theworldasastage.com/team-collaboration-is-hard-improvisation-training-can-help/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you left a meeting frustrated?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last time was every meeting. We are all working together on the same project, but it&amp;rsquo;s always the same :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;he can&amp;rsquo;t stop talking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;she always criticizes the new ideas and about minute details before we can even start building on it&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;he brings topics that had nothing to do with the initial agenda&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;she can&amp;rsquo;t stop cracking stupid jokes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;he doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand the big picture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;she is obsessed with her pointless ideas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;etc.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meetings are &lt;em&gt;improvised group collaboration&lt;/em&gt;: the participants don&amp;rsquo;t exactly know how they will contribute, and their reactions depend on others&amp;rsquo; behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We improvise collaboration with others all the time. In our relationship, in a store, at associations, with our family, etc. We take it for granted, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to learn how to interact with others. After all, this is the activity that we dedicate the most time to. By now, we should be experts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think that improvised group collaboration is one of the most difficult human activity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of considering myself as an expert, I now try to stay &lt;a href=&#34;http://theworldasastage.com/humble-and-demanding/&#34;&gt;humble and demanding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Humble&lt;/em&gt; because, as most people, I&amp;rsquo;ve never really worked on &lt;em&gt;collaboration&lt;/em&gt; except in day to day interactions. So, as for any activity I have to be humble and eager to learn how to be better at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Demanding&lt;/em&gt; because it&amp;rsquo;s possible to improve it and make a group collaborate in a much more efficient way than the sum of its parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-a-group-shines&#34;&gt;When a group shines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a group work together so effectively you couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe it was not scripted was in the improvised musical show of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theshowstoppers.org/&#34;&gt;The Showstoppers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4LZWg2vi6GE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this video you can hardly notice any mistake. But the Showstoppers are no different, they have the same problems we have in our meetings : unplanned and strange ideas, people insisting too much on what they have in mind, misunderstandings on what the story is about, etc. Their difference is that they trained to make their collaboration &lt;em&gt;flow&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improv is a mission-driven, goal-directed team activity where each participant is, at various times, both a leader and a follower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Izzy Gesell&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modern Improvisational theater is not new anymore, it has been first popularised by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viola_Spolin&#34;&gt;Viola Spolin&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keith_Johnstone&#34;&gt;Keith Johnstone&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; books, and now thousands of people are practicing it. Its techniques are used today outside of theater at the heart of innovation at &lt;a href=&#34;http://edition.cnn.com/2010/BUSINESS/02/18/improvisation.business.skills/index.html&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; and at companies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/3055380/why-top-companies-and-mba-programs-are-teaching-improv&#34;&gt;Google, Facebook or Apple&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.fr/scholar?hl=fr&amp;amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;amp;q=theater+improvisation&amp;amp;btnG=&#34;&gt;Even scientific studies begin to show the effectiveness of these tools on collaboration.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-can-we-learn-from-improvisation&#34;&gt;What can we learn from improvisation?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The techniques of the theater are the techniques of communicating
&lt;small&gt;Viola Spolin in &amp;ldquo;Improvisation for the theater.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as your work (or life) involves communicating with another human being, there are theater techniques and games to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;listening-and-building&#34;&gt;Listening and Building&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time I am the first to go on stage in an improvised play, I&amp;rsquo;m scared. When you start your scene, not knowing where the story is going, not knowing if your teammates and the audience will react positively to your offer, you only wish for one thing: &lt;em&gt;to never have gotten on the stage in the first place&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any person proposing something to a team is the same, the idea is still new and needs protection. Improvisers have created the mantra &lt;em&gt;yes, and&lt;/em&gt; to protect (saying &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;) and build on these new ideas (&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;). The &lt;em&gt;yes, and&lt;/em&gt;, is not just about being nice to a proposition out of kindness. It&amp;rsquo;s about &lt;strong&gt;being the best follower that has ever existed&lt;/strong&gt;, to make everything you can to make that idea work, to &lt;strong&gt;make your partner look beautiful&lt;/strong&gt;. So, if it fails, &lt;em&gt;it won&amp;rsquo;t be the mistake of anyone, it will be the learning for everyone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it&amp;rsquo;s the kernel of a movie idea or a fledgling internship program, the new needs protection. Business-as-usual does not. Managers do not need to work hard to protect established ideas or ways of doing business. The system is tilted to favor the incumbent. The challenger needs support to find its footing. And protection of the new-of the future, not the past must be a conscious effort.
&lt;small&gt;Ed. Catmull, president of Pixar in &amp;ldquo;Creativity, Inc.: Overcoming the Unseen Forces That Stand in the Way of True Inspiration.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trust&#34;&gt;Trust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://appliedimprovisation.network/events/2018-paris/&#34;&gt;2018 Applied Improvisation Network Conference in Paris&lt;/a&gt;. As we were discussing how to enable a group to be better at problem-solving, a theater director shared his surprise :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theater it can take years of work for building trust in a group before we even start to solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hard part of an improviser&amp;rsquo;s work is to build trust in a group. And this is firmly connected to how the group reacts to mistakes. Education systems everywhere in the world are formed by the same idea of giving feedback when we are wrong. Most of us have grown up in a culture where we felt ashamed to make mistakes. Instead, improvisers learn to embrace them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embracing mistakes is not only being ok with each error. It is also making mistakes as part of the learning process. Improvisers learn to have a positive reaction to errors, to make fun of them, to even build on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One night I was operating lights for the show Theatersports. It was my first time in the booth and I was taking everything very seriously, making sure I knew the correct sequences and controls. I was terrified of making a mistake, destroying the show and letting everyone down. Keith came into the lighting booth, casually looking around, asking, &amp;ldquo;Is this your first time doing lights?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo; I replied&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ah&amp;rdquo;, he said. &amp;ldquo;You need to make at least 3 mistakes or you haven&amp;rsquo;t done your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he left the booth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the whole show I was looking for any opportunity to take risks so that I could make my quota of mistakes. At the end of the show he said, &amp;ldquo;Patti, you made 2 mistakes  try again next time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keith used the logic of success to get me to make mistakes. He relieved me of the stress of fear of failure by giving me permission to make mistakes. He created an environment where I could take risk and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Patti Stiles in &amp;ldquo;The art of making mistakes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;freedom-and-constraints&#34;&gt;Freedom and Constraints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I ask friends to describe how they see improvisation they always tell me that &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s the liberating activity of doing whatever you want on stage and make fun of it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; If this were true, the Showstoppers&amp;rsquo; show would be a mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you go to an improv show, they may ask you for a suggestion, describe the ground rules, ask you to define some precise elements of the drama (the place, the characters jobs, their secret desires, etc.). It&amp;rsquo;s because improvisers also know that creation and collaboration are only possible under constraints. In a business environment, maintaining the equilibrium between freedom and constraints is difficult but indispensable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The temptation to lead as a chess master, controlling each move of the organization, must give way to an approach as a gardener, enabling rather than directing. A gardening approach to leadership is anything but passive. The leader acts as an &amp;ldquo;Eyes-On, Hands-Off&amp;rdquo; enabler who creates and maintains an ecosystem in which the organization operates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Stanley McChrystal from the U.S. Forces Afghanistan in &amp;ldquo;Team of Teams: New Rules of Engagement for a Complex World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;storytelling&#34;&gt;Storytelling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no gods, no nations, no money and no human rights, except in our collective imagination.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;small&gt;Yuval Noah Harari, Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of storytelling in organizations is not a new idea. A lot of books have explored how to build a compelling story. Even some events like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com&#34;&gt;TED talks&lt;/a&gt; have mastered the formula to the point that it&amp;rsquo;s always efficient&amp;hellip; but tend to be predictible as we all now see the recurring pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8S0FDjFBj8o&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storytelling is much more than telling a personal anecdote in the middle of a red circle. Improvisers work on building the unique story that this group, this audience, at this moment needs instead of following scripted tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brand is the set of expectations, memories, stories, and relationship that, taken together, account for a customer&amp;rsquo;s decision to choose one product or service over another
&lt;small&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-comes-next&#34;&gt;What comes next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning with the tools of Improvisational theater is a journey. There is no shortcut because it&amp;rsquo;s about being more self-aware of your habits and your surrounding. And then, you can decide, by yourself, the kind of person you want to be with others.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/horizontal-slim-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; width:100%;}
   
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://theworldasastage.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b&amp;amp;id=32885e90b3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
    Subscribe to the newsletter to receive a mail each new article about improvisation tools applied to businesses.
  &lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34; placeholder=&#34;email address&#34; required&gt;
    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b_32885e90b3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;management&#34; name=&#34;SIGNUPWHY&#34; class=&#34;required&#34; id=&#34;mce-SIGNUPWHY&#34;&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are not yet convinced and want more examples&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.fr/Applied-Improvisation-Leading-Collaborating-Creating/dp/1350014362/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1536582058&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=applied+improvisation&#34;&gt;Applied Improvisation: Leading, Collaborating, and creating beyond the theater&lt;/a&gt; for more examples of the application of theater techniques outside of the theater and their outstanding results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are convinced, and you want to start using these tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best advice is to find some improv training or workshops near your home to discover the process of improv training. If you prefer to read, you can check out the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.fr/Training-Imagine-Improvisational-Techniques-Creativity-ebook/dp/B015YFJ8GC/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1536582204&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=training+to+imagine&#34;&gt;Training to imagine&lt;/a&gt; to get a guided help on how to start applying improvisation in your organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Too long, didn&amp;rsquo;t read! Just watched the Showstoppers video, they are fantastic!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This other video is for you. Here is an example of the kind of improv training that makes the Showstoppers so amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5U_DwgtEny8&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The 5 informations every figure caption should have</title>
        <link>http://theworldasastage.com/the-5-informations-every-figure-caption-should-have/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://theworldasastage.com/the-5-informations-every-figure-caption-should-have/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;Each time I receive a 10 pages document explaining a scientific work on our data with several figures, my first reflex is to scroll and look at all the pictures without reading any text. This is no different from not reading the manual when you buy a new phone: &lt;em&gt;we are smart enough to understand&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://theworldasastage.com/img/beeers.png&#34; alt=&#34;Beeers&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for sure the number of beers of each type produced each year since 2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course afterward, I read the text carefully and realize how wrong I was. Even sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m not sure anymore of what really shows this figure. So you can imagine that when this remarkable result is transferred to a presentation, its real meaning is definitely lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__I believe that figures in a document must be self-explaining and engaging: __&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone should be able to understand them without reading the rest of the text.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone should be able to understand why you are showing this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The description must lead us to want to know more by reading the surrounding text.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve that, here is the checklist of 5 elements I tend to put in &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; figure (We are now sharing figures on computers, it&amp;rsquo;s not a problem anymore to have a 10 lines description).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factual description.&lt;/strong&gt; What are the different elements presented? what are the axes? what are the color for? etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This figure shows the number of beer brand depending on their color for three different kinds of beers: Pilsner (on top), Porter (middle) and Scotch Ale (on the bottom). The data is computed thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brewerydb.com/&#34;&gt;brewerydb&lt;/a&gt;. The y-axis corresponds to the number beer brand of a given color. The x-axis corresponds to the different colors (represented by their SRM color) and the color correspond to the color of the beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An example on how to read the figure.&lt;/strong&gt; Even with the factual description, it can be hard to understand how to read a chart so an example will help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, for a Pilsner with an SRM color of 10, the database count 50 different brands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why this figure is significant, what we can see?&lt;/strong&gt; If you are showing a picture, it&amp;rsquo;s because you consider it&amp;rsquo;s worth noticing. So develop your point of view, tell us what you interpret in this figure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing these three kinds of beers we can see that the primary color of each type is very different: the average SRM of Pilsner is 10, the one of Porter is 0, and the one of Scotch Ale is distributed between 0 and 22. Also, Scotch Ale is distributed between 0 and 22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your interpretation.&lt;/strong&gt; Here we want your opinion on the figure. You produced it, so you probably have your own idea of what to interpret.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This figure was created to test if with only the color of a beer we can determine its kind how different beer colors can be. We can see that some types like Pilsner can be associated with an exact color. Others, like Scotch Ale, are way more difficult to interpret only a given color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your questionings.&lt;/strong&gt; This part is optional. Most of the time a good figure brings the next questions, and the end of the description is the excellent place to place them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the color does not seem enough to interpret the kind of beer, it could be interesting to explore the color versus the BMI of the beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-the-caption&#34;&gt;beyond the caption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is only about the caption, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.data-to-viz.com/caveats.html&#34;&gt;the way you present your data is as important and can bring a lot of misunderstandings&lt;/a&gt;. But since we never stop producing figures when we work on data, ensuring good captions is an efficient way to ensure that everyone looking at your document got your point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your good practices about figures caption?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/horizontal-slim-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; width:100%;}
   
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://theworldasastage.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b&amp;amp;id=32885e90b3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
    Subscribe to the newsletter for more tips!
  &lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34; placeholder=&#34;email address&#34; required&gt;
    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b_32885e90b3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;management&#34; name=&#34;SIGNUPWHY&#34; class=&#34;required&#34; id=&#34;mce-SIGNUPWHY&#34;&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The leader&#39;s feedback</title>
        <link>http://theworldasastage.com/the-leaders-feedback/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://theworldasastage.com/the-leaders-feedback/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;I recently read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.knowyourcompany.com/announcing-a-guide-to-one-on-one-meetings-for-managers-and-employees-63d123a91db&#34;&gt;Guide to One to One Meetings&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.knowyourcompany.com/@clairejlew&#34;&gt;Claire Lew&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://knowyourcompany.com/&#34;&gt;Know Your Company&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the &lt;em&gt;best question&lt;/em&gt; to ask according to the guide is about manager feedback :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you like more or less direction from me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As managers, we crave feedback from our employees but I never thought of asking this question directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to ask for this kind of feedback in a team setting with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrum.org/resources/what-is-a-sprint-retrospective&#34;&gt;retrospectives&lt;/a&gt; or during a one to one with more general questions like &amp;ldquo;What do you think of the Company?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;What would you like to change?&amp;rdquo; But I never before asked for direct feedback about &lt;em&gt;how I manage&lt;/em&gt; them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried and the answer I received was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I&amp;rsquo;ve never thought about that! I&amp;rsquo;ll think about it for our next one to one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This answer clarified to me that giving feedback to a manager is not self-evident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;audience-feedback&#34;&gt;Audience feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improv workshops are organized around this idea of feedback. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keithjohnstone.com/&#34;&gt;Keith Johnstone&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Impro-Storytellers-Keith-Johnstone/dp/0878301054/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534784422&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=impro+for+storytellers&#34;&gt;Impro for storytellers&lt;/a&gt; talk about &lt;em&gt;being educated by the audience&lt;/em&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was young we thought that we should educate the audience, but I began to suspect that the audience should be educating us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But, Keith, we have the knowledge!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No, we don&amp;rsquo;t! We&amp;rsquo;re just guessing, but they know when to laugh, and when to be silent, and when to weep, and when to unwrap their chocolates. They may not be able to verbalize their knowledge, but they have it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Keith Johnstone - Impro for Storytellers (p. 31)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the same feeling about my team&amp;rsquo;s feedback. We&amp;rsquo;re just guessing, but they know when they feel bad, when they are disengaged, when our management is inadequate. &lt;em&gt;They may not be able to verbalize their knowledge but they have it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-two-minds&#34;&gt;The two minds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one helpful Keith Johnstone game to illustrate this difference between what &lt;em&gt;we think we should do&lt;/em&gt; and _what the audience want _: &amp;ldquo;What comes next with a committee.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A committee of three or four players are in front of the audience, facing the stage. They are the directors of the scene and they decide what will come next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An actor is playing what the committee decided and when they don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do, they ask &amp;ldquo;What comes next?&amp;rdquo; to the director and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audience is here to give direct feedback on the committee&amp;rsquo;s propositions.  They make a sound, &amp;ldquo;ding,&amp;rdquo; if they like the proposition and &amp;ldquo;Mmmm&amp;rdquo; if they don&amp;rsquo;t like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actor : What comes next?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Committee : You are walking in a Jungle
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Audience goes Ding!]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actor (start walking) : What comes next?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comittee : You discover a hidden temple
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Audience goes Ding!]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actor : What comes next?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comittee : An alien come out of the temple.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Audience goes Mmmm!]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comittee : You enter the temple!
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Audience goes Ding!]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actor (enters the temple) : What comes next?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game brings some very unexpected and funny situations. First, most of the time, the audience is unanimous, the entire audience knows what is good or bad even if it&amp;rsquo;s a spontaneous reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, the committee is no longer able to make an acceptable proposition to the audience. As if becoming a director, the committee&amp;rsquo;s members lost all that they like as an audience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This committee isn&amp;rsquo;t any different from the audience, but in the role of deciding what will happen, they become unaware of what should happen as if we had two minds that cannot efficiently work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking for feedback about your management is like asking the audience&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;they know&lt;/em&gt;.

&lt;link href=&#34;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/horizontal-slim-10_7.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
  #mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; width:100%;}
   
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;https://theworldasastage.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b&amp;amp;id=32885e90b3&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
    Subscribe to receive a weekly summary of new articles on leadership and improvisation!
  &lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34; placeholder=&#34;email address&#34; required&gt;
    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_c05d187131e01c7607fa4ae0b_32885e90b3&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;management&#34; name=&#34;SIGNUPWHY&#34; class=&#34;required&#34; id=&#34;mce-SIGNUPWHY&#34;&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you, how do you ask for feedback on your leadership style?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/gcDwzUGuUoI&#34;&gt;Photo by Davide Ragusa.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Creativity and programming languages</title>
        <link>http://theworldasastage.com/creativity-and-programming-languages/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://theworldasastage.com/creativity-and-programming-languages/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;Since the second half of the 20th century, we know that every language in which we can write a Turing Machine is a language with which we can write every single possible algorithm ever possible to write. Another way to say it is that for many years we know that all the programming language are equivalent, no one is able of more than any other, end of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://theworldasastage.com/img/dropmic.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Drop mic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, we could live happily in a world where every programmer is using the same language to talk to machines, but it&amp;rsquo;s entirely not the case. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_programming_languages&#34;&gt;According to Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, there are more than 700 languages (and with no doubt all programming language ever created is not on this page). And it&amp;rsquo;s only the &lt;em&gt;programming languages&lt;/em&gt;, we can add libraries that sometimes modify so much a programming language that you can&amp;rsquo;t recognize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://theworldasastage.com/img/programminglang-timeline.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Timeline of programming languages&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming languages are actually the hidden place of considerable creativity. I love art, cinema, theater and it&amp;rsquo;s in this particular field that I&amp;rsquo;ve been the most surprised by all the new idea we can discover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t believe me, this post is for you, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to answer these three questions :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we still create new languages?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are they really different?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it a creative activity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ultimate-programming-language&#34;&gt;The ultimate programming language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ultimate programming language has been tried long ago, and it didn&amp;rsquo;t stop the creation of new ones. Every programmer has his favorite language so this is not to start a war, I&amp;rsquo;m talking of a &lt;em&gt;ultimate programming language&lt;/em&gt; as a perfect idea that the language &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lisp_(programming_language)&#34;&gt;LISP&lt;/a&gt; illustrate perfectly in my opinion. This language was born in 1958 and as so is one of the first programming language ever created (14 years before &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_C_Programming_Language&#34;&gt;C&lt;/a&gt; and 32 years before &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_(programming_language)&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; that you probably know for example). Its syntax is straightforward, parenthesis, functions arguments&amp;hellip; and that&amp;rsquo;s all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;arg1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;arg2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;arg3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People think LISP is an ultimate language because some of his core concepts come directly from the dreams of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace&#34;&gt;Ada Lovelace&lt;/a&gt;: There are no differences between the data (inputs of our algorithms) and the language in which we process these inputs (the code we write). To put it in another way, we can use this language to modify its own behavior and adapt it to every problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LISP, created in 1958 can not only do everything (you can code a Turing machine), but it is also possible to modify its syntax as you need to adapt to your problem. Why would we need new languages after this one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reasons that are very similar to why it is powerful: LISP is hard to read, hard to use, hard to master and not necessarily the most efficient language for every application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must not judge a programming language only by what it can do or by its efficiency to do it but also by its ability to communicate an idea, an algorithm, to a computer. And, as it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes forgotten, to describe these algorithms to others humans!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believing that we need only one programming language is like believing only one art form is sufficient to communicate any idea. It&amp;rsquo;s assuming we should stop making movies, tv shows, comics, music because we already have books and it&amp;rsquo;s good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-best-way&#34;&gt;The best way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/G%C3%B6del-Escher-Bach-Eternal-Golden/dp/0465026567/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534543794&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=godel+escher&#34;&gt;Godel, Escher &amp;amp; Bach&lt;/a&gt; is a famous book which tries to connect the mathematician Godel, the artist Escher and the musician Bach. In the introduction to the French version, written by the author, Douglas Hofstadter explains that this French version is not an inferior version, neither a copy of the original version that would have lost some concepts during the process. No, he worked with the translators to make the same book, but in French. He presents this version as another projection of his ideas and that probably by reading the two text (if ever you are fluent in the two languages) you would get closer to the impression he wanted to transmit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A book or any work of art is only the transmission, as good as possible of what was of a mind of an artist. And sometimes some bugs occur: When Sam Ramy presents his horror movie &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dtsK7skqk9U&#34;&gt;Evil Dead&lt;/a&gt; and the public laugh in some scenes where it was supposed to be scared, it&amp;rsquo;s a bug (that will be used a lot in the following episodes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many works of art appear nowadays in several formats, sometimes freely adapted. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Martian-Young-Readers-ANDY-WEIR/dp/1785034677/ref=sr_1_8?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534544231&amp;amp;sr=8-8&amp;amp;keywords=the+martian&#34;&gt;The Martian&lt;/a&gt; first a book is getting stressful and addictive as an audiobook when the main character is telling us, day by day what happened to him. And of course, the movie presents incredible sightseeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other works of art seem to be stuck to one specific format. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Flowers-Algernon-Daniel-Keyes/dp/015603008X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534544373&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=flowers+for+algernon&#34;&gt;Flowers for Algernon&lt;/a&gt;, we read the journal of a retarded person who is having treatment to enhance his IQ. At the beginning of the book the writing is very hard to follow, and as we turn the pages, the novel evolves with the narrator IQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some writers use their medium to the limit. As if limited by their own language, they invent a new one. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Horde-Contrevent-Sc-Fiction-French-ebook/dp/B01A6X03EI/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534544565&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=damasio+horde&#34;&gt;La horde du contrevent&lt;/a&gt;, Alain Damasio invents a syntax to describe the wind. With commas, parenthesis and other signs, we can see the wind move, hit and kill on the pages of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://theworldasastage.com/img/horde.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;La horde du contrevent&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artists have in every epoch ask the question a programmer starts with: what is the best way to tell my story?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If programming were only about communicating to a computer, no programmer would invent a new syntax, a new language to describe what he is doing to his peers. A computer doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about that, it&amp;rsquo;s a machine after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;think-different&#34;&gt;Think different&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This far you must understand that there are several languages but, after all, what can make all these languages different? It&amp;rsquo;s still some cooking recipes, a list of instruction, some operation that we repeat, other done if some conditions are validated, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, of course, you can write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;condition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;action1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;();}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34; data-lang=&#34;ruby&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;action1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;condition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but it&amp;rsquo;s maybe not a reasonable justification for such a post&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the only differences between languages were this kind of small syntax changes, it would be pointless. But developers are way more creative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example: How to color a map with France, Belgium, Switzerland, and Germany with 3 colors (Red, Blue, Green) without having two adjacent regions with the same color?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing a &lt;em&gt;cooking recipe&lt;/em&gt; to solve this problem would be quite long as we would do what we are doing by hand: We try a color for the first country, use a différent one for the next one, etc. If at one point it&amp;rsquo;s impossible, we go back, and we change the colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to solve this problem is to use a &lt;em&gt;declarative language&lt;/em&gt;. For example, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prolog&#34;&gt;Prolog&lt;/a&gt;, we can write the following code  :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, we describe the fact that our colors are not the same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-prolog&#34; data-lang=&#34;prolog&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, we describe which are the neighboring countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-prolog&#34; data-lang=&#34;prolog&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;coloring&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;France&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Belgique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Suisse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Allemagne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;):-&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;France&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Belgique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;France&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Suisse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;France&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Allemagne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Belgique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Allemagne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Suisse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Allemagne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, we ask for the solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-prolog&#34; data-lang=&#34;prolog&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;coloring&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;France&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Belgique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Suisse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;Allemagne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is the algorithm? That&amp;rsquo;s precisely what seems magic with this way of programming: the algorithm &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; the description of the problem! We call this kind of language &lt;em&gt;declarative&lt;/em&gt;, we declare some rules, and after that, we can ask questions. One of the most popular declarative languages is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SQL&#34;&gt;SQL&lt;/a&gt;, a language used by most of the databases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no restriction on how should work a programming language. The only limits are the programmers&amp;rsquo; imagination. For example in the programming language &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.haskell.org/&#34;&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt;, we can define infinite lists! Of course, a computer can&amp;rsquo;t display all the elements of the list and crash if we ask for it but the programming language is &lt;em&gt;lazy&lt;/em&gt;, as far as we don&amp;rsquo;t ask, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some programming languages are more exercises of style like the &lt;em&gt;Shakespeare Programming Language&lt;/em&gt; where we code as if we were writing a Shakespeare play. For example, this program writes &amp;ldquo;Hello World.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Romeo](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romeo &amp;quot;Romeo&amp;quot;), a young man with a remarkable patience.
[Juliet](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juliet &amp;quot;Juliet&amp;quot;), a likewise young woman of remarkable grace.
[Ophelia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ophelia &amp;quot;Ophelia&amp;quot;), a remarkable woman much in dispute with Hamlet.
[Hamlet](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prince_Hamlet &amp;quot;Prince Hamlet&amp;quot;), the flatterer of Andersen Insulting A/S.

Act I: Hamlet&#39;s insults and flattery.
Scene I: The insulting of Romeo.
[Enter Hamlet and Romeo]
Hamlet:
You lying stupid fatherless big smelly half-witted coward! You are as
stupid as the difference between a handsome rich brave hero and thyself!
Speak your mind!
You are as brave as the sum of your fat little stuffed misused dusty
old rotten codpiece and a beautiful fair warm peaceful sunny summer&#39;s
day. You are as healthy as the difference between the sum of the
sweetest reddest rose and my father and yourself! Speak your mind!
You are as cowardly as the sum of yourself and the difference
between a big mighty proud kingdom and a horse. Speak your mind.
Speak your mind!
[Exit Romeo]
Scene II: The praising of Juliet.
[Enter Juliet]
Hamlet:
Thou art as sweet as the sum of the sum of Romeo and his horse and his
black cat! Speak thy mind!
[Exit Juliet]
Scene III: The praising of Ophelia.
[Enter Ophelia]
Hamlet:
Thou art as lovely as the product of a large rural town and my amazing
bottomless embroidered purse. Speak thy mind!
Thou art as loving as the product of the bluest clearest sweetest sky
and the sum of a squirrel and a white horse. Thou art as beautiful as
the difference between Juliet and thyself. Speak thy mind!
[Exeunt Ophelia and Hamlet]

Act II: Behind Hamlet&#39;s back.
Scene I: Romeo and Juliet&#39;s conversation.
[Enter Romeo and Juliet]
Romeo:
Speak your mind. You are as worried as the sum of yourself and the
difference between my small smooth hamster and my nose. Speak your
mind!
Juliet:
Speak YOUR mind! You are as bad as Hamlet! You are as small as the
difference between the square of the difference between my little pony
and your big hairy hound and the cube of your sorry little
codpiece. Speak your mind!
[Exit Romeo]
Scene II: Juliet and Ophelia&#39;s conversation.
[Enter Ophelia]
Juliet:
Thou art as good as the quotient between Romeo and the sum of a small
furry animal and a leech. Speak your mind!
Ophelia:
Thou art as disgusting as the quotient between Romeo and twice the
difference between a mistletoe and an oozing infected blister! Speak
your mind!
[Exeunt]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as strange as it is, this language is powerful enough to write a Turing machine, and as a consequence, any algorithm can be written with it. Yes, Microsoft World can be written in Shakespeare Programming Language, and it would be quite impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;human-communication&#34;&gt;Human communication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of differences in programming languages as the previous one. And if you can find a lot of programming languages that&amp;rsquo;s partly because of these kinds of design choices. It even seems that some paradigms of programming languages have the same roots as the cultural differences in human communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Culture-Map-Breaking-Invisible-Boundaries/dp/1610392507/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1534546316&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+culture+map&#34;&gt;The Culture Map&lt;/a&gt;, Erin Meyer presents 7 criteria to analyze cultural differences :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** communication:** is the context very important or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** feedback:** direct or indirect negative feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** leading:** egalitarian or hierarchical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** deciding:** consensual or top down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** trusting:** according to what is done or via our relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;** disagreeing:** confrontation or avoiding confrontation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;time management:&lt;/strong&gt; linear or non-linear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These criteria seem to correspond also to essential programming designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, some libraries use a &lt;em&gt;high context&lt;/em&gt;. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://rubyonrails.org/&#34;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt;, only writing &lt;code&gt;has_many :friends&lt;/code&gt; in a file named &lt;code&gt;user.rb&lt;/code&gt; is enough for the tool to understand that we have a database named &lt;code&gt;Users&lt;/code&gt; and another one &lt;code&gt;Friends&lt;/code&gt; and that the database &lt;code&gt;Friends&lt;/code&gt; will store a reference to the &lt;code&gt;Users&lt;/code&gt; database for each entry. So with only a small line of code, we avoid lines of descriptions. And as human communication, this kind of high context suppose that everyone is sharing the same context or some problems will occur quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to make feedback is also a severe difference between languages. &lt;em&gt;Variables&lt;/em&gt; have what we call a &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt;. For example &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; is an integer and &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; a string. Some programming languages are nice, you can write &lt;code&gt;1+&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; and the language will convert the string in an integer to do the sum. The other will be more strict and crash because they can&amp;rsquo;t add a string and an integer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More interesting even is the time management. As a cooking recipe, we can think as a programming language as a linear time algorithm where we do the operations line by line in order. But some languages start the next line without waiting for the previous one to finish, they are asynchronous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are only some examples of the differences between languages. Creating a language follow most of the time a need to communicate something in a particular way. We can find the same with books, some authors create a new world full of imaginary creatures to tell their story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is surprising with programming languages is that other people will use these weird creations and make it their primary tool, even if it requires a lot of adaptation. If very few worlds created by authors are used by others, for programming language it&amp;rsquo;s widespread. Most of the programmers can use several languages and adapt their choice to their needs. It&amp;rsquo;s as if a writer decided to use Italian to write his romance and switched to English for his thriller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;communicate-with-machines&#34;&gt;Communicate with machines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New languages are of course also created to make execution by machines more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the internet and the Web, it&amp;rsquo;s rarely only one computer which is processing the data but way more in parallel. As a consequence, these last years programming languages have been created to make this task easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a conclusion, there are a lot of programming languages, and there will probably be a lot more in the future. Because culture changes, because habits change because needs change, because it&amp;rsquo;s interesting, because it&amp;rsquo;s entertaining because it&amp;rsquo;s one of the ways humans have found to express their creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a translation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.podcastscience.fm/dossiers/2018/04/20/creativite-et-langages-de-programmation-2/&#34;&gt;Podcast Science 319&lt;/a&gt;, a weekly popular science podcast in french.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;références&#34;&gt;Références&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics#Computer_science&#34;&gt;A lot of different syntaxes to do the same thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_programming_languages&#34;&gt;Programming languages comparison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.fr/Seven-Languages-Weeks-Bruce-Tate/dp/193435659X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1524127105&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=seven+languages+in+seven+weeks&#34;&gt;Seven languages in seven weeks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Humble and Demanding</title>
        <link>http://theworldasastage.com/humble-and-demanding/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://theworldasastage.com/humble-and-demanding/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday lunch, you were eating your usual sandwich with this fantastic ham and cheese. You were so &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; eating this meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With each movement we could feel that you were enjoying it. Sometimes a simple sandwich can evoke a smile. Your co-workers around the table were not paying any particular attention to you but were unconsciously affected by you: their posture was influenced by the dirty plastic bag you left on the middle of the table and by the gestures you make when you eat. Some days you start a discussion over lunch. Some other days like yesterday, it&amp;rsquo;s with the eyes that the silent communication takes place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scene is banal, this scene is boring, this scene is real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add a stage and an audience and anyone of us will start doing some strange things. We&amp;rsquo;ll start exaggerating our movements to make this &lt;em&gt;sandwich eating&lt;/em&gt; more interesting. Others around the table will overreact to each bite you take as if just being normal was not enough. And the public will be bored, not because the scene is necessarily boring but because suddenly, with the presence of the stage, some actors have decided to &lt;strong&gt;play&lt;/strong&gt; the scene instead of &lt;strong&gt;live&lt;/strong&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;fr&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;und&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/gCd8FTeyNU&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/gCd8FTeyNU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dark Stock Photos (@darkstockphotos) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/darkstockphotos/status/920316418830282752?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;17 octobre 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-theater&#34;&gt;What is Theater&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one paradox of theater. We want to tell real life stories but by adding a stage and an audience, the moment and the truth disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So you need to start over to learn how to act&lt;/em&gt;, how to be influenced by the other actors and how to have emotions. We train to be able to reproduce in front of an audience an everyday scene like eating a sandwich, a simple act that every one of us manages to do when we are involved. This is what we call being an actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So you need to start over to learn how to move in space&lt;/em&gt;, how to move your body, how to place yourself in your environment and how to orchestrate the actors, space and movement to reproduce something we can believe in. This is what we call being a director.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So you need to start over to learn how to tell a story&lt;/em&gt;, capture what is interesting, what is true and what is meaningful. Just being able to express and maintain emotions, to follow characters and to make this particular moment important. This is what we call being a writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s what an improviser is trying to do in real time: being an actor, a director and a writer as the scene is being created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-humble-improviser&#34;&gt;The humble improviser&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to do a one week intensive improv workshop with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.againproductions.fr/&#34;&gt;Again! Production&lt;/a&gt; in summer 2017 after doing improv for around 10 years. I think the most surprising aspect of this workshop was to admit to myself what seems obvious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;improvisation is hard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first idea you meet in improv is &amp;ldquo;Yes, and&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; which mean we should accept as much as we can, we should be positive and  we should avoid our negative habits when playing with others. Too often, these essential ideas are replaced by the idea that improvisational theater is the place where you can do whatever you want&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; without any care of if you are actually playing truthfully or if you are just the next stereotypical elderly,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; without any care of if you actually recreate a scene worth remembering or if you are just two players standing in the middle of the stage,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; without any care of if you are actually writing a beautiful story and not looking for the best jokes combo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop reminded me that this essential concept was not there to hide the most important element: improvising is this crazy art form where during the scene, you are trying to be the theater &lt;strong&gt;director&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;actor&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;writer&lt;/strong&gt; at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s hard, that&amp;rsquo;s probably impossible, that&amp;rsquo;s exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-demanding-improviser&#34;&gt;The demanding improviser&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Again! Productions&lt;/em&gt; teachers of the workshop, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ianparizot.com/&#34;&gt;Ian Parizot&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp;
Emmanuel De Chavigny, have an educational background in theater in addition to their improvisation training and experience. It makes their workshop (and their courses) rigorous and highly demanding. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve ever met another group that sets such high standards in improv as they do. The teachers expect a lot from you and this pushed me further to improve as an improviser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://theworldasastage.com/img/again-2017.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Crédit photo : Luis-carlos Davila&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that &lt;em&gt;Again! Productions&lt;/em&gt; vision is that improvisational theater doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be a subculture comparing to classical theater and that a good improv show can bring you just as much emotions, story and beautiful ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to attain this you need to accept to fully immerse yourself in improv, &lt;em&gt;to affect and be affected&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-everyday-improviser&#34;&gt;The everyday improviser&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;Humble &amp;amp; Demanding&lt;/strong&gt; approach is not restrained to the Improv or Theater world. Startups call it the &lt;em&gt;Minimum Viable Product&lt;/em&gt;, they concentrate on a little task in a bigger picture and try to do it as best as they can. What we can learn from the improv world is that you can also apply this approach to communication and to your behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again! Production is doing a lot of workshops &amp;amp; shows (even in english!) that you can find on their website : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.againproductions.fr&#34;&gt;https://www.againproductions.fr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve never done Improv (go find a workshop!), you can read &amp;ldquo;Impro&amp;rdquo; by Keith Johnstone as an introduction to it and its links with life in general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    </channel>
</rss>