<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
    <title>Training on The world as a stage</title>
    <link>https://theworldasastage.com/tags/training/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Training on The world as a stage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://theworldasastage.com/tags/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
        <title>Training : Why don&#39;t I have more ideas?</title>
        <link>https://theworldasastage.com/training--why-dont-i-have-more-ideas/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://theworldasastage.com/training--why-dont-i-have-more-ideas/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In front of this computer since hours I&amp;rsquo;m looking for how to start this article. How the find &lt;em&gt;the idea&lt;/em&gt; that will make it meaningful. I turn the music on and the distraction off and start to look around me to think &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thinking_outside_the_box&#34;&gt;outside the box&lt;/a&gt;. Two hours ago I planed to write this article about my first improvisation training. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to train us on behavior and creativity topics. This first training is about what I&amp;rsquo;m struggling with now and what expressed one day one of my employee,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I have more ideas?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s exactly the topic of this training, &lt;em&gt;why don&amp;rsquo;t we have more ideas&lt;/em&gt; and how to train to make it more easy. At this point you must ask how someone with exactly the same problems will have any help. First, because building the story in the moment is what I do in theater improvisation. Next, because thanks to improvisation, I know that this first feeling is normal and can happen, you can&amp;rsquo;t be a full time creative/productive genius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use regularly &lt;a href=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/team-collaboration-is-hard-improvisation-training-can-help/&#34;&gt;applied improv&lt;/a&gt; to train my team on behavioral and creativity topics. You can find all the trainings &lt;a href=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/tags/training/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you are looking for resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I present this kind of trainings to non-improvisers, I first precise what is the topic and the objective to it. The objective of this first training is to : &lt;strong&gt;Feel and understand why we block ideas&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Train to act on it, to be more spontaneous&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This training lasted 2H with a group of 5 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I organise this workshop in different parts that I will present below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before : A form to have my team start thinking of the topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A brief introduction of the training and the objective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A warm-up : As in sport we need to warm-up our bodies and minds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short Games : Theater use games to explore topics, these games are good to work on a particular subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scenes : Using what we learned during the games, we practice in some short scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next : At the end we decide what to apply in our work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important part of Short Games and Scenes are the debrief. Contrary to usual learning, in improv and when you learn about your behaviour it&amp;rsquo;s by debriefing as a group on what just happened that you can discover what are your reflexes and actions that you want to be more aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are what and how we did all these events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-first-questions&#34;&gt;Some first questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One week before the start of the training, I sent to every participants 4 simple questions :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is spontaneity for you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How spontaneity is linked with your work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why aren&amp;rsquo;t we spontaneous?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When is the last time you didn&amp;rsquo;t share one of your ideas with your team? What did you feel? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you share it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These questions have a double objective. First they will help you to adapt the rest of the training to the people coming. But must importantly, they help to make the people coming start thinking of the topic. So don&amp;rsquo;t expect to have everyone&amp;rsquo;s answer, it&amp;rsquo;s a cold warm-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;answers&#34;&gt;Answers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time I had to answer these questions or ask them, the answers came very similar. Yours will of course have some differences showing the culture of the group you&amp;rsquo;ll work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is spontaneity?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spontaneity is seen as very &lt;em&gt;positive&lt;/em&gt; in our mind. We link it with &lt;em&gt;honesty&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;transparency&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;authenticity&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;emotion&lt;/em&gt;, etc. These are all very important topics in our daily life that as unsurprisingly hidden in business world because they are also linked with &lt;em&gt;vulnerability&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vulnerability is the birthplace of love, belonging, joy, courage, empathy, and creativity. It is the source of hope, empathy, accountability, and authenticity. If we want greater clarity in our purpose or deeper and more meaningful spiritual lives, vulnerability is the path.
&lt;small&gt;Brown, Brené. Daring Greatly&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How spontaneity is linked with work??&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you ask your people what spontaneity can bring to their work, they directly can see the link with innovation. &lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a way to react faster and better&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;to find new ideas&lt;/em&gt; and to &lt;em&gt;use the different point of views&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why aren&amp;rsquo;t we spontaneous?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some reasons of preventing spontaneity are clear in our mind :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;we are polite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;we juge ourselves&lt;/em&gt; : &lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s too late&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not original enough&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;we are scared&lt;/em&gt; : &lt;em&gt;we don&amp;rsquo;t want to look stupid&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;we don&amp;rsquo;t want to say something wrong&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;we don&amp;rsquo;t want to be juged&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these answers point the same elements, we don&amp;rsquo;t share ideas as a protective behavior against others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-of-the-training&#34;&gt;Presentation of the training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to make the introduction on the topic short but it&amp;rsquo;s important to be clear on what we will work and how will be done the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an internal member of the team, I first state the most important : we are working on being a better group, on improving our behavior together. So there is no one, even me as the trainer, who is &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you work on improving a group, it makes no sense that one person is better than the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I remind them that human behaviors can be a tricky topic as it&amp;rsquo;s link on how, as people, we act and react with other person. So, even trying to do my best to make this training useful and safe, I&amp;rsquo;ll make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I play low status, and I&amp;rsquo;ll explain that if the students fail they&amp;rsquo;re to blame me. Then they laugh, and relax, and I explain that really it&amp;rsquo;s obvious that they should blame me, since I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be the expert; and if I give them the wrong material, they&amp;rsquo;ll fail; and if I give them the right material, then they&amp;rsquo;ll succeed.
&lt;small&gt;Keith Johnstone&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I state back the topic : &lt;em&gt;today the work is on spontaneity&lt;/em&gt;. And I tell them that they will have notes and resources about this training (this article) available after the training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;warm-ups-15min&#34;&gt;Warm-ups / 15min&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warm-up exercices are usualy safe games where the participants can warm their body and escape their mind from their work or worries to be fully present on the training.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;div class=&#34;improv-game&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Zip, Zap, Zop&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;
      &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;source: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;probably the most widely used warm-up game.
    &lt;/small&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In a circle participants pass a &lt;em&gt;Zip!&lt;/em&gt; noise to each other. One player can decide to say &lt;em&gt;Zap!&lt;/em&gt; to change the direction of the noise or to say &lt;em&gt;Zop!&lt;/em&gt; to skip the next player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game is perfect to make every member of the group present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/warmup/zipzapzop/&#34;&gt;More details on the details, process and debrief &gt;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;



  &lt;div class=&#34;improv-game&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Mind meld&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;
      &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;source: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Discovered at the Barcelona Improv Group.
    &lt;/small&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In a group, a first player says &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt; when he thinks of a word. Then when a second player thinks he knows the word of the first player he says &lt;em&gt;2&lt;/em&gt;. Finally together they say &lt;em&gt;1,2,3&lt;/em&gt; and their world. If they have the same word, it&amp;rsquo;s a Mind Meld!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good warmup to put a group in the same energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/warmup/mindmeld/&#34;&gt;More details on the details, process and debrief &gt;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;exercises-30min&#34;&gt;Exercises / 30min&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the energy is there, I start the training with two games on our topic.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;div class=&#34;improv-game&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Giving presents&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;
      &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;source: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Viola Spolin, Keith Johnstone
    &lt;/small&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Player A offers an imaginary present to player B. Player B defines what is the present and show his happiness on what he has just been offered! The pair continues the same action back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game is very simple and very good to show how hard it can be to define what should be the easiest thing : a present we would like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theworldasastage.com/improv-games/exercises/presents/&#34;&gt;More details on the details, process and debrief &gt;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This exercice is a perfect way to feel all the block we can put when we try to generate ideas. In this game the only rule about the ideas to generate is to make you happy. A good present can be a postcard, a glass of beer or a good book but we prefer to find good reasons to avoid these obcious ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psycotic thought : The fear of your idea being lanelled &lt;em&gt;mad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obscene Thought : Individual reject idea that could offend others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unoriginal Thought : Individuals often block their imaginations when they feel unoriginal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defer the judgement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No - Yes but - Yes - Yes and / 5-10min&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A et B, A raconte une histoire, B ne répond que Non (puis Yes but, puis Yes, puis Yes and). Puis on échange les roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A chaque étape :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quelle impression ça fait de ne recevoir que des non? de commencer ses phrases par&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quelle impression ça fait de ne se faire dire des phrases commençant par&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A la fin : Quel était la version que vous préfériez? Dans quel role? Pouruqoi?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quel lien vous faites avec notre travail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scenes&#34;&gt;Scenes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One sentence at a time / 30min&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stratégies de bloquage :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Etre négatif&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wimping : accept but no adding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancelling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gossiping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidetracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being original&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gagging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-next-30min&#34;&gt;Conclusion - Next! / 30min&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qu&amp;rsquo;est-ce que vous retenez d&amp;rsquo;aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qu&amp;rsquo;est-ce que vous avez appris?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quel lien avec notre travail?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Après ce travail, qu&amp;rsquo;est-ce que vous allez :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commencer à faire que vous ne faisiez pas?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrêter de faire parce que ça ne marche pas?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuer à faire parce que ça marche ou parce que vous voyez des nouveaux usages?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quel jeu/truc/lien on se donne pour continuer à appliquer ces principes les deux prochaines semaines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If I knew how to do this (ndlr: teaching) I wouldn’t be there… I would create a franchise and go on a boat on Mediterranean sea&amp;rdquo; K.J.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;« You should not be attached to ideas, they are only tools »&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Keith Jhonstone, imagination is suppressed in three different ways :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psycotic thought : The fear of your idea being lanelled &lt;em&gt;mad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obscene Thought : Individual reject idea that could offend others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unoriginal Thought : Individuals often block their imaginations when they feel unoriginal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am coaching, I bypass the psychotic and obscene filters by asking the team to pretend to be a famous person or character that might ignore the filters — Improving agile teams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is spontaneity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le fait de dire/faire quelque chose de manière brute: sans sur-réflechir, rapidement après l&amp;rsquo;arrivée de l&amp;rsquo;idée, et avec franchise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;une forme d&amp;rsquo;intelligence, capacité d&amp;rsquo;expression ultra-rapide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Réagir &amp;ldquo;naturellement&amp;rdquo; à ce qui nous est proposé, en n&amp;rsquo;ayant pas peur de dire quelque chose qu&amp;rsquo;on n&amp;rsquo;a pas particulièrement réfléchi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Être spontané, c&amp;rsquo;est agir ou s&amp;rsquo;exprimer sans anticipation des réactions ou du jugement d&amp;rsquo;autrui et de soi-même. C&amp;rsquo;est s&amp;rsquo;exprimer aussi souvent avec émotion sans parfois réfléchir ou reformuler sa pensée.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why spontaneity is linked to business?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je pense qu&amp;rsquo;il est plus efficace d&amp;rsquo;être spontané dans le monde du travail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dans mon travail, ça prendrait la forme d&amp;rsquo;une capacité de réaction aux bugs/problèmes théoriques rencontrés&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dans les phases créatives, on a besoin de spontanéité pour avoir de nouvelles idées&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La spontanéité permet de profiter de ce que chaque membre d&amp;rsquo;un groupe de travail peut apporter. Elle permet de recenser une large palette d&amp;rsquo;idées et de susciter des échanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are we sometimes not spontaneous?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;politesse/vivre en société (pour nous= ne pas casser l&amp;rsquo;organisation de la réunion); ratio utilité/temps-à-passer en dessous du seuil :P ; mauvais retours des fois précédentes =&amp;gt; auto-censure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Par peur de l&amp;rsquo;échec, par volonté d&amp;rsquo;optimisation. L&amp;rsquo;approche Greedy est pas toujours la bonne&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;parce qu&amp;rsquo;on veut trop réfléchir à son idée avant de la proposer. Parce qu&amp;rsquo;on a peur de se tromper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pas assez de confiance/préparation dans l&amp;rsquo;idée à exposer. Difficulté de prise de parole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last time you didn&amp;rsquo;t share an idea, why? And what did you feel?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C&amp;rsquo;était dû aux points de la question précédente!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Un peu de frustration et d&amp;rsquo;incompréhension. Ce qui m&amp;rsquo;a retenu : le fait qu&amp;rsquo;on était depuis un moment sur ce problème&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La peur de dire une bêtise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surtout de la frustration . Ce qui m&amp;rsquo;a retenu : Pas forcément le bon moment (sujet éloigné de celui sur la table) , idée pas assez fouillée.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;warm-up&#34;&gt;Warm up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Word association with spontaneity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anecdotes about spontaneity and thermometer to know if others agree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hat game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;games&#34;&gt;Games&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mad / Bad / Stupid suggestions with characters representing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presents / what&amp;rsquo;s in the box improving agile teams (all the elements to prepare it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Tuesday / accept this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes but&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted narrative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invisible ball&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slap game (+story)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color advance (problem solving)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expert interview with real or false expert topics (problem solving)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast food stanislavski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;yes-and-protocol&#34;&gt;Yes And Protocol&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the 3D process :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duplicate : Repeat what the product owner said&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe : Find something in the suggestion that you like. Tell the product owner what it was and why you liked it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop : Make a suggestion on how the idea could be improved, even if you think the idea is already good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ressources&#34;&gt;Ressources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impro for storytellers (spontaneity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impro (spontaneity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impro notes &amp;ldquo;interacting with patients&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Training to imagine activity sheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The art of makimg mistakes david martinez p73&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving agile teams, spontaneity chapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://home.cc.gatech.edu/je77/75&#34;&gt;Directing Improv Workshops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    </channel>
</rss>